<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Vates astrologicus, or, England's astrological prophet, fortelling what is likely to befall Great-Britain and Ireland, particularly the great and famous city of London as also France, Holland, Spain, Germany, Poland, Italy, Sicily, Apalia, Bohemia, Turkey, and indeed all Europe, but more especially the see of Rome, for twenty years together, beginning March 10, 1683, and ending March 10, 1702 : likewise astrological judgments of the effects of that famous triple conjunction of Saturn and Jupiter, being thrice repeated in that regal sign Leo, the great dignities of the Sun and Jupiter: also some remarks upon the eclipses, and more especially upon that great and famous visible eclipse of the sun, July 2, 1684 : with twenty years predictions from some of the most eminent mutual aspects of the planets, and eclipses of the luminaries, and annual revolutions of the  sun : here are also many hieroglyphicks representing the future state and changes of the world : to which is added a treatise of the pestilence, both for the prevention and cure thereof / by Richard Kirby.</title>
            <author>Kirby, Richard, b. 1649.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1683</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 173 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 31 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A47492</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing K623</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R17066</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">11859638</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 11859638</idno>
            <idno type="VID">50004</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A47492)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 50004)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 499:20)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Vates astrologicus, or, England's astrological prophet, fortelling what is likely to befall Great-Britain and Ireland, particularly the great and famous city of London as also France, Holland, Spain, Germany, Poland, Italy, Sicily, Apalia, Bohemia, Turkey, and indeed all Europe, but more especially the see of Rome, for twenty years together, beginning March 10, 1683, and ending March 10, 1702 : likewise astrological judgments of the effects of that famous triple conjunction of Saturn and Jupiter, being thrice repeated in that regal sign Leo, the great dignities of the Sun and Jupiter: also some remarks upon the eclipses, and more especially upon that great and famous visible eclipse of the sun, July 2, 1684 : with twenty years predictions from some of the most eminent mutual aspects of the planets, and eclipses of the luminaries, and annual revolutions of the  sun : here are also many hieroglyphicks representing the future state and changes of the world : to which is added a treatise of the pestilence, both for the prevention and cure thereof / by Richard Kirby.</title>
                  <author>Kirby, Richard, b. 1649.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[12], 48 p. : ill., port.  </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Thomas Malthus,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1683.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Errata: p. [4].</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Bodleian Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Astrology --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Prophecies.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-07</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-08</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="frontispiece">
            <pb facs="tcp:50004:1"/>
            <p>
               <figure>
                  <p>vt. vmbra: Sic. vitae:</p>
                  <byline>English. fe.</byline>
                  <figDesc>portrait of Richard Kirby (?)</figDesc>
               </figure>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:50004:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>
               <hi>VATES ASTROLOGICUS:</hi> OR, ENGLAND'S <hi>Aſtrological Prophet,</hi> Fortelling what is likely to befall GREAT-BRITAIN and IRELAND, Particularly the Great and Famous CITY of <hi>LONDON:</hi> AS ALSO <hi>France, Holland, Spain, Germany, Poland, Italy, Sicily, Apalia, Bohemia, Turkey,</hi> and indeed all <hi>Europe,</hi> but more eſpecially the See of <hi>Rome,</hi> for Twenty Years together, beginning <hi>March</hi> 10. 1683, and ending <hi>March</hi> 10. 1702.</p>
            <p>LIKEWISE Aſtrological Judgments of the Effects of that famous Triple Conjunction of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter,</hi> being thrice repeated in that Regal Sign <hi>Leo,</hi> the great Dignities of the Sun and <hi>Jupiter.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>ALSO Some Remarks upon the Eclipſes, and more eſpecially upon that great and famous viſible Eclipſe of the Sun, <hi>July</hi> 2. 1684.</p>
            <p>WITH Twenty Years Predictions from ſome of the moſt eminent Mutual Aſpects of the Planets, and Eclipſes of the Luminaries, and Annual Revolutions of the Sun.</p>
            <p>Here are alſo many Hieroglyphicks repreſenting the future State and Changes of the World.</p>
            <p>To which is added a Treatiſe of the PESTILENCE, both for the Prevention and Cure thereof.</p>
            <p>By <hi>Richard Kirby,</hi> Student in Aſtrology and Phyſick.</p>
            <q>Coeli ennarant Dei fortis, &amp; opus manuum ejus indicat expanſum eorum, <bibl>
                  <hi>Pſalm 19.1.</hi>
               </bibl> The hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vens declare the glory of God, and the firmament ſheweth his handy works, &amp;c.</q>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>Thomas Malthus,</hi> and are to be ſold at his Shop at the <hi>Sun</hi> in the <hi>Poultry,</hi> 1683.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="publishers_advertisement">
            <pb facs="tcp:50004:2"/>
            <p>
               <hi>Cataſtrophe Mundi:</hi> Or, <hi>Merlin</hi> Reviv'd, in a <hi>Diſcourſe</hi> of <hi>Prophecies</hi> and <hi>Predictions,</hi> and their Remarkable Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compliſhment. With Mr. <hi>Lilly</hi>'s <hi>Hieroglyphicks</hi> exactly cut; and Notes and Obſervations thereon. As alſo a <hi>Collection</hi> of all the ancient (reputed) <hi>Prophecies</hi> that are Extant, touching the Grand Revolutions like to happen in theſe latter Ages. <hi>By a Learned Pen.</hi> To be Sold by <hi>Thomas Malthus</hi> at the Sun in the <hi>Poultrey.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="to_the_reader">
            <pb facs="tcp:50004:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>TO THE IMPARTIAL <hi>and</hi> UNDERSTANDING READER.</head>
            <p>DEar Country-men, if the time now preſent, and thoſe I ſee approaching, make me the doleful Meſſenger of more Misfortunes, the indifferent Reader will, I hope, excuſe me, for Truth is Truth, and a Horſe is a Horſe, if I may ſo call it; no profit hath induced me to put Ink in Pen, and Pen to Paper; nor no deſire of Fame by publiſhing a Work of this Nature, which of it ſelf is ſo contrary to the Opinions of moſt Men; beſides, many will deſpiſe this Work for my meanneſs, and want of Education, being my ſelf no Collegian of either <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>niverſity; it's not ſet forth with Eloquence, our Art denying us that Luſtre, but Truth is Eloquence, and Eloquence is Truth; no ignorant Mans envy do I care for, I have hitherto lived, and ſhall ſtill, ſo long as the Divine Providence is over me; but I could wiſh no man would carp at the Subject I write of; yet ſince it is eaſier to Carp than to Copy, let them Carp that will; but let none miſtake my meaning, in this Subject: When I write this Planet, or that Conſtellation did, or doth ſuch a thing; I mean the influence of that, or that Planet is ſuch, or ſuch, according to Natural Cauſes, it inclines, God permitting, to ſuch or ſuch Acts, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Let Man live meerly as a Natural Man without ſpark of Grace, the influence then predominates, but where Grace rules, the Stars obey, this I mean in Mens Qualities: The general good do I aim at, and that men fore-knowing the Evils to come, might more patiently abide them, and with leſs trouble of mind receive them; it's probable this may procure me many Enemies, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe
<pb facs="tcp:50004:3"/>
its of Aſtrology, but why it ſhould I know not; if they are both Chriſtians and Proteſtants, ſo am I: Do theſe Honour their King, I do, whom God Preſerve, and ſend him many a happy and proſperous day to live. Let my willingneſs to ſerve my King and Country bury my failings, I write Cordially; <hi>Scotland</hi> and <hi>England</hi> ſhall in full meaſure of time ruine the greateſt Enemies of the Proteſtants, and make them flee like Chaff be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the Wind: God is now doing a great Work, his Gliſtering Signs affrighten our Enemies, for their horrid Plots againſt us, he ſhakes his Darts over them, and inclines to puniſh them with a ſharp Sword. The great God of Heaven has been exceeding merciful unto us in delivering our Nation from to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tal Ruine, and we may truly ſay, <hi>Si deus nobiſcum, quis con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tra nos.</hi> He uſeth in all ſublunary affairs fit means and proper inſtruments to perform what he intends, againſt which there is no reſiſting.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>Rich. Kirby.</signed>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>Fullham,</hi> 
                  <date>February the <hi>10th 1683.</hi>
                  </date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="errata">
            <head>ERRATA.</head>
            <p>PAge the 1. line 2. for <hi>nibil</hi> read <hi>nihil.</hi> p. 2. l. 31. r. <hi>Swedeland</hi> and <hi>Piemont,</hi> l. 39. r. <hi>their.</hi> p. 3. l. 23. r. <hi>aerial.</hi> p. 5. l. 24. r. <hi>Perſons,</hi> l. 25. <hi>and he in Sextil.</hi> p. 8. l. 24. r. <hi>Judgment.</hi> p. 9. l. 17. r. <hi>anima,</hi> l. 39. r. <hi>the Influence.</hi> p. 10. l. 35. r. <hi>Celeſtial.</hi> p. 11. l. 44. r. <hi>diſcovered</hi> for <hi>detected.</hi> p. 12. l. 1. r. <hi>Scheme,</hi> l. 23. r. <hi>watry.</hi> p. 13. l. 2. <hi>this good will.</hi> p. 15. l. 14. r. <hi>but agunt,</hi> l. 27. r. <hi>Sixth.</hi> p. 17. l. 27. r. <hi>to the.</hi> p. 18. l. 11. r. <hi>Mars.</hi> p. 21. l. 20. r. <hi>Prince doth frown,</hi> l. 23 r. <hi>aerial.</hi> p. 24. l. 19. r. <hi>Coeleſtial.</hi> p. 25. l. 13. r. <hi>Coeleſtial,</hi> l. 21. r. <hi>Coeleſtial.</hi> p. 26. l 15. r. <hi>Carolſtade.</hi> p. 28. l. 43. r. <hi>Countries under</hi> Virgo <hi>be invaded.</hi> p. 30. l. 5. r. <hi>and</hi> England. p. 33. l. 9. r. <hi>the Common.</hi> p. 34. l. 11. r. <hi>which is March,</hi> l. 10. <hi>Saturn <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>pp<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>s.</hi> p. 38. l. 34. r. <hi>firſt.</hi> p. 39. l. 30. dele <hi>er.</hi> p. 40. l. 2. r. <hi>their third and laſt.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="illustrations">
            <pb facs="tcp:50004:3"/>
            <p>
               <figure/>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb facs="tcp:50004:4" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <figure/>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb facs="tcp:50004:4" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <figure/>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb facs="tcp:50004:5"/>
               <figure/>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb facs="tcp:50004:5" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <figure/>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb facs="tcp:50004:6"/>
               <figure/>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb facs="tcp:50004:6" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <figure/>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb facs="tcp:50004:7"/>
               <figure/>
            </p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:50004:7" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>England's Aſtrological-Prophet.</head>
            <p>
               <table>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Time.</cell>
                     <cell cols="4">☉ Long.</cell>
                     <cell cols="4">☉ Apog.</cell>
                     <cell rows="9">
                        <hi>Nibil eſt tam oc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>c<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>ltem quod non ſit detegendum:</hi> No<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing is ſo ſecret but it ſhall be known and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vealed, &amp;c.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Epoche.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                     <cell>d.</cell>
                     <cell>m.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                     <cell>d.</cell>
                     <cell>m.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Year 1600.</cell>
                     <cell>9.</cell>
                     <cell>20.</cell>
                     <cell>55.</cell>
                     <cell>23-</cell>
                     <cell>3.</cell>
                     <cell>5.</cell>
                     <cell>44.</cell>
                     <cell>8.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>80.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>36.</cell>
                     <cell>16.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>1.</cell>
                     <cell>22.</cell>
                     <cell>10.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>2.</cell>
                     <cell>11.</cell>
                     <cell>29.</cell>
                     <cell>31.</cell>
                     <cell>20.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>2.</cell>
                     <cell>4.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Febr.</cell>
                     <cell>1.</cell>
                     <cell>28.</cell>
                     <cell>9.</cell>
                     <cell>11.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Dayes 8.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>7.</cell>
                     <cell>53.</cell>
                     <cell>7.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Hours 28.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>51.</cell>
                     <cell>45.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Min. 13.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>32.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Mid. Long. ☉</cell>
                     <cell>11.</cell>
                     <cell>27-</cell>
                     <cell>57.</cell>
                     <cell>34</cell>
                     <cell>3.</cell>
                     <cell>7.</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>32.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Apog. ſub.</cell>
                     <cell>3.</cell>
                     <cell>7.</cell>
                     <cell>8.</cell>
                     <cell>32.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Anom. Res.</cell>
                     <cell>8.</cell>
                     <cell>20.</cell>
                     <cell>49.</cell>
                     <cell>02.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Equa ad.</cell>
                     <cell>00.</cell>
                     <cell>2.</cell>
                     <cell>2.</cell>
                     <cell>26.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>☉ place is</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>Vi. z.</hi> in</cell>
                     <cell>♈</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
               </table>
            </p>
            <p>The FIGURE followeth, &amp;c.</p>
            <figure>
               <head>
                  <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> ⚹ ♂, ad <g ref="char:quadrine">□</g> ☉ &amp; ☿, ♀ ☍ ♄ &amp; ♃, ☿ ☌ ☉, Sol in Aries, March the 10th, 8 Hours 11 Min mane, <hi>Londini,</hi> Lat. 51 deg 32, 1683</head>
            </figure>
            <p>
               <pb n="2" facs="tcp:50004:8"/>In this Figure of the Sun's ingreſs into <hi>Aries, common</hi> and <hi>fixed</hi> Signs poſſeſs the Angles, <hi>viz.</hi> the Aſcendent and Mid-heaven, and <hi>Jupiter</hi> with that glorious Lamp of Heaven, the <hi>Sun,</hi> rules, and hath power in the North and Weſt Angles; <hi>Mercury,</hi> Lord of the aſcendent is in the ſign of the twelfth, the manſion of <hi>Sorrow</hi> and <hi>Affliction,</hi> and there retrograde and combuſt of the Sun; and the <hi>Moon</hi> is in the eight in her Detriment, in ſquare of the Sun and Mercury: Therefore I fear but little of <hi>good</hi> can be expected this half year; the vulgar and common people are ſtill dejected, and make great Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plaint for the Want of Trade, and Moneys, and all ſuch things as are neceſſary for their Supportment: and beſides, the Moon in the 8. doth certainly ſhew, that a great many people muſt yield to pale <hi>Death</hi> this year, who will not be denyed by the <hi>Princes of the Earth</hi> when their time is come: But the Moon being the Earth's attendant, and but a ſecondary Planet, cannot ſignifie ſuch grand alterations in the World as the primary and ſuperiour Planets do; eſpecially when they happen to be conjoyned together, as here they are in the angle of the Earth, and there oppoſed by <hi>Venus</hi> from the 10th, which ſheweth, that many Fears and Troubles ſhall fall upon men, and that their Hearts and Minds ſhall be poſſeſſed with Jealouſies and ſtrang Apprehenſions, and that not without juſt cauſe; for you muſt note, that <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter</hi> in the fourth, retrograde, ſhews ſome <hi>ſecret Plot</hi> and Deſign a hatching; but let the Contrivers thereof look to it, for it will be moſt happily and timely diſcovered; for it was never known that ever <hi>Wo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men</hi> were good Counſel-keepers. Therefore I judge, that <hi>Venus</hi> in the 10th, in Conjun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction with the <hi>Dragon's Tayl,</hi> and being in oppoſition to <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter,</hi> ſhews ſome Woman or Women ſhall diſcover the Villanies of this Plotting Council, &amp;c. And be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſides, it ſignifies a Dark Obſcure <hi>Air,</hi> Earthquakes, and Deſtruction to the Fruits both of the Trees and Earth. Alſo; it ſignifies <hi>Povorty</hi> and Indigency; alſo a Scarceneſs of Fruits and Proviſions, great Miſchiefs, Cold in the extremity, grievour Fears, Anxie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, Terrors and Troubles, much Want and Scarcity of the Fruits of the Earth, and a ſuperfluity of Evils, Torments and Grievances, incident to thoſe places under the ſigns <hi>Leo</hi> and <hi>Aquarius,</hi> which be <hi>Rome, Italy, Cicily, Bohemia, Turky, Phenicia</hi> or <hi>Chal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dea;</hi> for <hi>Satura</hi> and <hi>Jupiter</hi> da<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ts their Evil Influence moſtly into the <hi>Courts of Prince,</hi> and will ſhew their dire Effects to thoſe Countries and Regions which are under the ſigns <hi>Leo</hi> and <hi>Aquarius,</hi> as <hi>Tartary, Muſcovia, Sweedland, Piedmount, Hamborough, Breem, Trent, Bavaria</hi> and <hi>Salizburgh.</hi> And further, you muſt note, ſuch Poſitions as theſe, do alwayes denote Strife, Trouble and Confuſion amongſt the Grandees of <hi>Europe,</hi> with many Informations againſt great Perſons in the Courts of Princes, and thoſe which are of the higheſt Degree and Quality: beſides, I judge this hath been a long time a contriving, ſince this Oppoſition is made from <hi>fixed</hi> ſigns and angles, &amp;c. Now <hi>Saturn</hi> is in a ſign wherein he hath no eſſential Dignities, which ſhews, that <hi>ancient people</hi> ſhall deſert their Habitaaions, and be drawn out of one place into another, it may be out of thei own natural ſoil; for here is no loſs than four of the Planets retrograde, which motion ſhews thoſe places under the ſigns <hi>Ares, Leo, Libra</hi> and <hi>Aquarius</hi> to be in a ſtrang kind of poſture at the time of this ingreſs. But at the latter end of <hi>March,</hi> and the beginning of <hi>April,</hi> the t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>o ſuperiours become both <hi>direct,</hi> by which motion they meet in conjunction in <hi>May,</hi> at which time I fear much <hi>Treachery,</hi> with Tumults and Commotion of Arms in many places of <hi>Europe:</hi> for, take this for an approved Apho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſm, that <hi>when any of the ſuperiours, viz.</hi> Saturn, Jupiter <hi>or</hi> Mars, <hi>are in conjunction, or any other malevolent Configuration one of another, there happens great and manifeſt Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terations in this Elementary World, with Alterations of Laws, Cuſtoms, Kingdoms and Empires:</hi> Therefore <hi>Rome</hi> prepare thy ſelf to entertain Showers of Judgment; for a
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:50004:8"/>
               <hi>Plague</hi> is threatned unto thee; and I am apt to believe, this is thy declining Age; for the Lord hath declared in the 6th Chapter of <hi>Ezekiel,</hi> and the 3d Verſe, <hi>Behold I, even I, will bring a Sword upon you, and I will deſtroy your high places:</hi> Verſe 4. <hi>And your Altars ſhall be deſolate, and your Images of the Sun ſhall be broken; and I will caſt down your ſlain Men before your Idols:</hi> Verſe the 11th, <hi>For they ſhall fall by the Sword, by the Famine, and by the Peſtilence:</hi> Verſe the 13th, <hi>And you ſhall know that I am the Lord, when their ſlain Men ſhall be among their Idols:</hi> Verſe the 14th, <hi>So will I ſtretch mine Hand upon them, and make their Land waſte and deſolate, from the Wilderneſs unto</hi> Diblath, <hi>in all their Habita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions; and they ſhall know that I am the Lord.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>I had almoſt forgot <hi>Cauda</hi> in the 10th, in that humane ſign <hi>Aquarius;</hi> which ſhews, that Rulers, Great Men and Landlords ſhall be very Injurious and <hi>Tyrannical</hi> over their Subjects, Servants and Tenants, and ſhall afflict, <hi>tax</hi> and grind their Faces beyond com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon humanity and honeſty; and Tradeſmen will deviſe wayes in their Trades to cozen and <hi>cheat</hi> their Neighbours; and the Chief Rulers ſhall have <hi>Croſſes</hi> and Troubles, and per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>haps ſome of their Honours ecclipſed; and ſtill all this ſhall be carried on by a cloak and ſhew of <hi>Friendſhip,</hi> and that by ſome <hi>She Counſel:</hi> and all theſe things will fall in particular upon thoſe places which are under the ſigns <hi>Leo</hi> and <hi>Aquarius;</hi> perhaps <hi>Tartaria, Muſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>covia, Aethiopia, Media, Italy, Damaſco, Bohemia</hi> and <hi>Rome</hi> in particular.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>England!</hi> I could ſay ſomething to thee too, but it is no great matter whether I do or not, ſince thou doſt not care for hearing it.</p>
            <p>Now, as to the Diſeaſes this half year, they are many, and are ſignified by <hi>Mars</hi> in the 6th, in <hi>Libra,</hi> and <hi>Venus</hi> lady thereof, who is poſited in the tenth in <hi>Aquarius,</hi> both a rial ſigns; thus <hi>Venus</hi> being oppoſed by <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter,</hi> who are with two notable fix<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed Stars of the nature of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Mars,</hi> then by conſequence it muſt be Pains or Swel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings in the <hi>Leggs</hi> and <hi>Knees,</hi> occaſioned from ſome <hi>cold</hi> cauſe, with violent Pains in the <hi>Head</hi> and <hi>Heart,</hi> alſo Afflictions in the <hi>Reins</hi> and <hi>Kidneys</hi> either by <hi>Stone</hi> or Gravel lodg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed in thoſe parts, and conſequently pains in the Bladder, with a hot Urin; nay in this Caſe we may expect the <hi>French Pox</hi> to be very frequent, and chiefly to thoſe Perſons which are of the Nature of <hi>Mars</hi> and <hi>Venus;</hi> and beſides, we may juſtly fear the <hi>Plague,</hi> or ſome other Epidemical Diſeaſe equivolent, too near approaching; for <hi>Mars</hi> in <hi>Librae</hi> ſignifies Diſeaſes occaſioned by <hi>Corruption of Blood</hi> through Chollar, as the Peſtilence, Burning Feavours, Tertian and Quotidian Agues, Megrim, Carbuncles and Plague Sores; Burnings, Scaldings, Ringworms, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>liſters, Yellow Jaundiſe, Bloody Flux, Fiſtula's, Shingles, Calentu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>es, Small Pox, Meazles, and all Diſeaſes of Chollar. Let no man think that I predict theſe things poſitively; for the Heavens ſhew only natural Inclinations, not poſitive Actions; therefore, if we bend our Wills to ſerve the true God, and ſtrive to taſte of the Cup of <hi>Repentance,</hi> we need not to fear but that the Lord will remove the bitter Cup far from us, which he hath ſo long forewarned us of, as hath been plainly ſeen by our mortal Eyes, as by Three Suns, Ships and Armies Fighting in the Air, likewiſe two Dreadful Comets, Fiery Darts, and great Meetings of the ſupetiour Stars, beſides many Ecclipſes of the Sun and Moon, ſome of them being Total, and near Centural too.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="4" facs="tcp:50004:9"/>IN the next place, I ſhall proceed to the Judgment of the Autumnal half year, which this year begins <hi>September</hi> 12-14 Hours; 58 Minutes paſt Noon, as may be ſeen by the Calculation at large.</p>
            <p>
               <table>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Time.</cell>
                     <cell cols="4">☉ Long.</cell>
                     <cell cols="4">☉ Apog.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Epoch.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                     <cell>d.</cell>
                     <cell>m.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                     <cell>d.</cell>
                     <cell>m.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Years 1600.</cell>
                     <cell>9.</cell>
                     <cell>20.</cell>
                     <cell>55.</cell>
                     <cell>2.</cell>
                     <cell>3.</cell>
                     <cell>5.</cell>
                     <cell>44.</cell>
                     <cell>8.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>80.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>36.</cell>
                     <cell>16.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>1.</cell>
                     <cell>22.</cell>
                     <cell>10.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>2.</cell>
                     <cell>11.</cell>
                     <cell>29.</cell>
                     <cell>31.</cell>
                     <cell>20.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>2.</cell>
                     <cell>4.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Auguſt.</cell>
                     <cell>7.</cell>
                     <cell>29.</cell>
                     <cell>30.</cell>
                     <cell>44</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>41.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Dayes 11.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>10.</cell>
                     <cell>50.</cell>
                     <cell>32.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Hours 15.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>36.</cell>
                     <cell>57.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Min. 44.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>1.</cell>
                     <cell>48.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Mid. lodg ☉</cell>
                     <cell>6.</cell>
                     <cell>2.</cell>
                     <cell>3.</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                     <cell>3.</cell>
                     <cell>7.</cell>
                     <cell>9.</cell>
                     <cell>3.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Apo. ſub.</cell>
                     <cell>3.</cell>
                     <cell>7.</cell>
                     <cell>9.</cell>
                     <cell>3.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Anom. Res.</cell>
                     <cell>2.</cell>
                     <cell>24.</cell>
                     <cell>53.</cell>
                     <cell>57.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>equa ſub.</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                     <cell>2.</cell>
                     <cell>3.</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>☉ place.</cell>
                     <cell>6.</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>Viz.</hi> in</cell>
                     <cell>♎</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
               </table>
            </p>
            <p>The FIGURE followeth.</p>
            <figure>
               <head>
                  <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> ⚹ ♄ ad ⚹ ♃ &amp; ♀, ♀ ☌ ♃, ♂ ad <g ref="char:quadrine">□</g> ♃ &amp; ☿ ⚹ ♂ Septemb. 13. 2. hou. 58 min. mane, 1683: Lat. 51. 32. <hi>Londini.</hi>
               </head>
            </figure>
            <p>
               <pb n="5" facs="tcp:50004:9" rendition="simple:additions"/>A judicious Eye may perceive by this Poſition, that all things at the preſent ſeem to be at a ſtand, and yet many cloſe and ſecret Deſigns are hatching, if not P<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ots contri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving; for all the angles are fixed, and the Planets themſelves ſubterranean, and no leſs than five of them much debilitated: <hi>Jupiter</hi> is in his detriment, and <hi>Venus</hi> in her fall, and both ſquared by <hi>Mars,</hi> who is in oppoſition to <hi>Gemini, London</hi>'s Aſcendent, which portends much Sorrow and Affliction to the people in general<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> as well in <hi>England,</hi> as in forreign parts. But what theſe Changes ſhall be, I am not able to divine; therefore I ſhall leave it to ſwift-winged Time to unfold the Myſtery: Yet to wind the ſtrings a little higher, and that without Injury to Aſtrology or any man's Opinion, I conclude, that the Actions and Affairs of States and Kingdoms will be eminent and conſiderable in many places of <hi>Europe,</hi> chiefly in <hi>Spain, Rome, Italy, Holland, France, Hungary</hi> and <hi>Bohe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mia,</hi> and in many more places too tedious for me here to relate. This poſition threatens them with Wars, Bloodſhed, Mutanies, Commotions of Arms, and with many ſtrang and unnatural Diſeaſes, &amp;c. Beſides, I perceive <hi>Mars</hi> to be Lord of the 9th, which is the Houſe of <hi>Religion,</hi> which ſeems unto me as if he had a mind to turn Preacher; a prety Fellow to make a Pariſh Prieſt on? And beſides, <hi>Saturn</hi> in the aſcendant, juſt lea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving the ſign <hi>Leo,</hi> and entering into <hi>Virgo;</hi> the great Dignity of <hi>Mercury,</hi> doth inform me that the great Conjunction of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter</hi> doth begin to operate, yet but very Slowly, for within ſome few months <hi>Saturn</hi> becomes Retrograde and ſo enters into <hi>Leo</hi> a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gain, therefore I do believe we ſhall not ſee its effects in a full meaſure untill the year 1686. yet I do fear the <hi>plague</hi> or ſome other epidemical diſtemper long ere that time. God of his mercy divert his Judgments and ſend them far from us, even to the Remote parts of the earth, for <hi>Saturn</hi> in the aſcendant doth much trouble, perplex and diſturb the hearts of many perſons with Terrors and fears, but the moon having dignities in the Eleventh, and ſhe defluxing from a ſextil of <hi>Saturn</hi> and applying to a ſextil of <hi>Jupiter</hi> and <hi>Venus</hi> doth ſhew that many will labour to ſecure themſelves and their Friends too; and truly their la<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bour will be very great, for the <hi>Moon</hi> is in her fall, and in that <hi>Treacherous</hi> ſign <hi>Scorpio,</hi> which makes me much to Fear, that many of them will be but pretended Friends. And to conclude, <hi>Mercury</hi> being diſpoſer of <hi>Jupiter</hi> and <hi>Venus,</hi> and he ſextil of <hi>Mars,</hi> doth ſhew many Pamphlets and Libels ſhall be diſperſed Abroad, on purpoſe to Diſturb and Perplex the Hearts and Minds of good honeſt well meaning Perſons, who do ſtrive to Settle and Compoſe all former Difference, but let thoſe ill confuſed Agents look to it, for the <hi>Devil</hi> never brings them into a <hi>Praemunire,</hi> but he leaves them there to work their own Redemp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion. And ſo I ſhall proceed to the conſideration of the Ecclipſes this year. Thus three times will the Glorious Lamps of Heaven be deprived of their Light, viz. Once the <hi>Sun</hi> and Twice the <hi>Moon,</hi> the firſt is of the <hi>Sun</hi> on January the 17th, near three a Clock After<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>noon <hi>Viſible,</hi> it falls in the firſt face of <hi>Aquary,</hi> it cauſeth publique Sorrow and Sadneſs: The ſecond is of the <hi>Moon</hi> on the firſt of February, about three Afternoon <hi>Inviſible,</hi> it falls in the laſt face of <hi>Leo:</hi> This incites the People and Armies, to new Actions and Attempts of War. The third and laſt Ecclipſe is likewiſe of the <hi>Moon,</hi> which falls on July the 28th; at eight a Clock in the Morning <hi>Inviſible,</hi> this falls in the ſecond face of <hi>Aquary,</hi> which por<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tends much hurt both to the Fruits and Seeds of the Earth; and that perticularly to thoſe Places under the Lunations Ecclipſed; which you may read at large in my very good friend Mr. <hi>Cooleys Clavis of Aſtrology,</hi> page the 92, and 93, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>And ſo I ſhall proceed, to the conſideration of the figure of the <hi>Suns</hi> ingreſs into <hi>Aries,</hi> for the year 1684. beginning March the 9th, 1 hour 57 minutes paſt noon, as it doth ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pear by this following Calculation.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="6" facs="tcp:50004:10"/>
               <table>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Time.</cell>
                     <cell cols="4">☉ Long.</cell>
                     <cell cols="4">☉ Apog.</cell>
                     <cell rows="9">By the <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dolphin Tables,</hi> &amp;c.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Epoch.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                     <cell>d.</cell>
                     <cell>m.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                     <cell>d.</cell>
                     <cell>m.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Years 1600.</cell>
                     <cell>9.</cell>
                     <cell>20.</cell>
                     <cell>55.</cell>
                     <cell>2.</cell>
                     <cell>3.</cell>
                     <cell>5.</cell>
                     <cell>44.</cell>
                     <cell>8.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>80.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>36.</cell>
                     <cell>16.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>1.</cell>
                     <cell>22.</cell>
                     <cell>10.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>3.</cell>
                     <cell>11.</cell>
                     <cell>29.</cell>
                     <cell>17.</cell>
                     <cell>00.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>3.</cell>
                     <cell>4.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>February</cell>
                     <cell>1.</cell>
                     <cell>28.</cell>
                     <cell>9.</cell>
                     <cell>11.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>10.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Dayes 9.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>8.</cell>
                     <cell>52.</cell>
                     <cell>15.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Hours 2.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>4.</cell>
                     <cell>56.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Min. 59.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>2.</cell>
                     <cell>26.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Mid. lodg. ☉</cell>
                     <cell>11.</cell>
                     <cell>27.</cell>
                     <cell>57.</cell>
                     <cell>27.</cell>
                     <cell>3.</cell>
                     <cell>7.</cell>
                     <cell>9.</cell>
                     <cell>33.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Apo. ſub.</cell>
                     <cell>3.</cell>
                     <cell>7.</cell>
                     <cell>9.</cell>
                     <cell>33.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Anom. Res.</cell>
                     <cell>2.</cell>
                     <cell>20.</cell>
                     <cell>47.</cell>
                     <cell>53.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>equa ad.</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                     <cell>2.</cell>
                     <cell>2.</cell>
                     <cell>33.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>☉ place.</cell>
                     <cell>6.</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>Viz.</hi> in</cell>
                     <cell>♈</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
               </table>
            </p>
            <p>The FIGURE followeth.</p>
            <figure>
               <head>
                  <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> ⚹ ☿ ad <g ref="char:trine">△</g> ♃ &amp; <g ref="char:quadrine">□</g> ♃, ♀ <g ref="char:trine">△</g> ♄ ♂ ad <g ref="char:trine">△</g> ♄, March the 9th, 1 hours, 57 mi. paſt noon, 51. 32.</head>
            </figure>
            <p>The Angles of this figure are all fixed, and <hi>Saturn</hi> is in the aſcendant Retrograde with a notable fixed Star, viz. <hi>Corleonis,</hi> and applies to a time of <hi>Mars,</hi> by his Retrograde motion who is poſited in the 9th, in Conjunction with <hi>Venus,</hi> who is Ruler of the Mid-heaven, upon which poſition I Judge his Holineſs feels himſelf begin to Decline, yea, both he and
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:50004:10" rendition="simple:additions"/>
his whole Dominions; for <hi>Saturns</hi> long tranſit through the ſign <hi>Leo,</hi> beſides his t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>iple Conjunction with <hi>Jupiter</hi> in the ſame, makes him begin to look about him, and he finds it the beſt way to make Friends with his neighbouring Nations, as <hi>England, France, Ger<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>many, Polonia, Denmark, Paleſtine, Naples, Syria, Burgundy,</hi> and many more places which are under the ſign <hi>Aries,</hi> as may be ſeen by his application to the time of <hi>Mars</hi> in this figure, but all this will not do; for <hi>Saturns</hi> continuance almoſt three years in the ſign <hi>Leo,</hi> will ſhew it's di<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>e effects to thoſe places under that Conſtellation and it's oppoſit ſign <hi>Aquary,</hi> therefore <hi>Rome</hi> once more I forewarn thee, to prepare thy ſelf to entertain ſho<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>s of Judgment, for thou haſt taken delight in ſpilling of <hi>Blood;</hi> and now ere long thou may'ſt live to drink it, for as thou haſt been a <hi>Perſecutor</hi> of the People of God, in due time thou may'ſt and muſt look to be called to an Account. And beſides, <hi>Saturn</hi> in the aſcendant, with <hi>Corleonis,</hi> and there weak and much debilitated, Denotes miſchief and trouble to People in their proper Perſons, alſo ſtrange Infirmities, with many Vexations and Misfortunes, and that perticular to thoſe Places under the ſigns <hi>Leo</hi> and <hi>Aquary,</hi> which you may read in Mr. <hi>Coleys Clavis of Aſtrology,</hi> page the 92 &amp;c. Therefore I ſhall for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bear reciting any perticular place, but proceed in further conſideration of the figure, as thus, <hi>Jupiter</hi> in the ſecond according to the Rules of Art, doth promiſe increaſe of fortune to the People in General, and that they ſhould Enjoy the Fruits of the Earth, and Reap their Crops in due ſeaſon, and my reaſon is this, becauſe <hi>Jupiter</hi> is in <hi>Virgo,</hi> a ſign of the Earthly Triplicity, but conſidering <hi>Jupiter</hi> is in his Detriment, and <hi>Mercury</hi> much Debili<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tated, who is his diſpoſer, and applies to his Oppoſition, <hi>Mercury</hi> being Lord of the 11th likewiſe, Therefore I Judge that many Perſons who are put in place of great Truſt, and though they be counted worth <hi>Thouſands,</hi> will turn <hi>Bankrupts,</hi> and ſo Deprive and De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fraud the Widow and the Fatherleſs of their proper Rights: But conſidering the <hi>Moon</hi> is a general Significator of the common People, and ſhe poſited in the Mid-heaven in her Exal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tation, and no ways Impedited but in ſextil of <hi>Mercury,</hi> and applying to a <hi>trine</hi> of <hi>Jupiter,</hi> Therefore I Judge that we in <hi>England</hi> ſhall be in a Good and Proſperous Condition, and Enjoy our Libertys, and that we ſhould be in good Eſteem and Credit with our Superiours and Governours; but I muſt tell you by the way, that <hi>Cauda</hi> in the ſixt, and <hi>Saturn</hi> Lord thereof in the Aſcendant, doth foreſhow Strang and Unwholeſom Ai<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>, which may cauſe many Prodigious Diſeaſes both to Man and Beaſt, as Violent afflictions at the Heart, Weakneſs in the Knees, Pains in the Back, Melancholy Fears and Grief, a Decay or Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſumption in the Reins and Inward parts, alſo Corruption of the Blood, Black Jaundis, Palſie, Vain fears, Gouts of all ſorts, and many Strange and Unheard of Diſtempers: Neither ſhall we be free from many <hi>Open Enemies,</hi> ſtriving to Oppoſe and Diſturb the Government, with many ſtrang Reports from ſeveral parts beyond the Seas, as may be ſeen in the Figure. <hi>Mars</hi> in the 9th, ſhews dangers in Travail both by Sea and Land, as ſudden Shipwracks, occaſioned by ſeveral Storms and Tempeſts, and many of our Ships Plundered by Py<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ats; for <hi>Carden</hi> ſaith, if <hi>Mars</hi> be poſited in a fie<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>y ſign, great heat follows <hi>Burning of Houſes,</hi> with great Lightnings and Wars; Example that great Fire in Wapping, in 82. Which was Predicted by me in my Almanack the ſame Year; at which time <hi>Mars</hi> was in <hi>Aries,</hi> as here he is now. But I judge much of this Evill will be abated this Year; for the <hi>Sun</hi> and <hi>Venus</hi> Beautifies the Ninth houſe, as much as <hi>Mars</hi> deforms it, therefore hope the beſt. And beſides <hi>Venus</hi> tyes the ſword of <hi>Mars</hi> from do<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing much damage, though ſhe be in her Detriment; for <hi>Venus</hi> is <hi>Venus</hi> ſtill, let her be where ſhe will: Yet <hi>Venus</hi> and the <hi>Sun</hi> in the 9th, Uſually ſhews Men of Religious orders, to Flight and Remove from one place and houſe to another: And again I am apt to believe, that Men ſhall Dream <hi>true Dreams;</hi> and perform many long Journeys with Safety, and Profit,
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:50004:11"/>
and Gain thereby; and that they ſhould be lovers of the Law both of God and Man: and eſteem of all good Learning, &amp; ſtrive to be Virtuous: And beſides <hi>Souldiers</hi> ſhould be very Succesful, and perform many notable Exploits, and overcome their Enemys, and gain good Eſteem and Honour thereby. And my reaſon is this, becauſe <hi>Mars</hi> is ſo Strong in his own Eſſential Dignities, and ſo well ſupported by <hi>Venus,</hi> &amp;c. In the next place I ſhall give you an account of the Luminaries Ecclipſed this Year: Four times will the Heavenly Lamps be deprived of their Glorious Light viz. twice the <hi>Sun</hi> and as often the <hi>Moon;</hi> the firſt will be an Ecclipſe of the <hi>Sun,</hi> which falls on the ſixth day of January, about ſix at night Inviſible, it falls in the laſt face of <hi>Capricorn:</hi> it denotes Famine and Tumultary motions of Princes. The ſecond Ecclipſe is of the <hi>Moon,</hi> and it falls on June the ſeventeenth, at three of the clock in the Morning, in the firſt face of <hi>Capricorn,</hi> and Viſible; this denotes Suggeſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions among Men, and Untimely Death or Miſcheif to <hi>ſome Illuſtrious and Noble Man.</hi> The third will be an Ecclipſe of the <hi>Sun,</hi> on July the ſecond, about three of the clock After<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>noon, Viſible to us in <hi>England,</hi> and almoſt <hi>Total,</hi> for above <hi>two thirds</hi> of the <hi>Suns</hi> body will be darkened, it falls in the laſt face of <hi>Cancer,</hi> this denotes Sedicious Hidropical Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eaſes, and cauſeth Peſtilent and grievous Mortalities, and cauſeth Winds and alterations of the Weather, which much troubles the Air; it alſo dryeth up Rivers and Fountains, like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe it denotes the Death of <hi>ſome great Perſon or Ruler.</hi> The fourth and laſt Ecclipſe is of the <hi>Moonr</hi> it falls on the eleventh day of December, at eleven at night <hi>Viſible,</hi> it happens in the firſt face of <hi>Cancer,</hi> this cauſeth Wars and Innundations or Overflowing of the Sea banks, &amp;c. In Mr. <hi>Cooleys Clavis of Aſtrology,</hi> you may find what places are moſt like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly to Suffer and Feel the effects of theſe Ecclipſes, which is <hi>Scotland, Holland, Burgundy, Saxony, Granado, Zeland, Pruſia, Haſia, Macedonia, Oxford, Guant, &amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>JJudgment Upon That great and Famous Ecclipſe of the Sun, 1684, Wedneſday, 2d July 2 hours 40 minutes afternoon, at which Time, about two thirds of the Suns body will be darkned from our ſight &amp;c.</p>
            <figure>
               <head>The Sun Ecclipſed <hi>July</hi> the 2d, 2 Hours 40 paſt noon, 1684. <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> ☌ ♂ ☿ ⚹ ♃ &amp; ☌ ☉, ☿ ☌ ♂, ♂ ad ⚹ ♃, &amp;c.</head>
            </figure>
            <p>
               <pb n="9" facs="tcp:50004:11"/>The <hi>Sun</hi> and <hi>Moon</hi> have obtained the Adminiſtration or Ruling of the <hi>Heavens,</hi> the <hi>Sun</hi> is Lord of all Elementary Virtue, and the <hi>Moon</hi> by Virtue of the glorious <hi>Sun,</hi> is <hi>Miſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>triſs</hi> of Generation, Increaſe or Decreaſe. Hence <hi>A<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>bumaſor</hi> ſaith, <q>that by the <hi>Sun</hi> and <hi>Moon</hi> Life is Infuſed into all things; by him ſo many glorious <hi>Lamps of Heaven</hi> do ſhine, by him the Elements ſtand, the Winds blow, the Plants flouriſh, living Creatures have ſence:</q> Which therefore <hi>Orpheus</hi> calls the Enlivening Eyes of the <hi>Heavens,</hi> the <hi>Sun</hi> gives light to all things of it ſelf, and gives it Plentifully to all things, not only in the <hi>Heaven</hi> and <hi>Air,</hi> but <hi>Earth</hi> and <hi>Deep,</hi> he produces the <hi>Day</hi> here and the <hi>Night</hi> there, here it is fair Weather, by and by Thunder, Storms and Lightning, he paſſeth into Waters, then into Hail, being ever one and the ſame Artifict, of ſix hundred Arts, he paints the Clouds with Azure colour, Cloaths the tops of the Mountains with Gold, what ever Creatures are either in the Heavens or in the Earth, all of them do love the <hi>Sun</hi> riſeing, Nature being Guide: It is the property of all Living Creatures to rejoyce with the Light and Refreſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of the <hi>Sun;</hi> whatſoever Good we have, as <hi>Jamblicus</hi> ſaith, we have it from the <hi>Sun</hi> alone, or from it through other things, therefore it is called <hi>Fons vitae</hi> the Fountain of Life, or <hi>lux Mundi</hi> the Light of the World, or <hi>Oculus Mundi</hi> the Eye of the World, or <hi>Anama Mundi</hi> the Soul of the World: Hence therefore many of the Platoniſts placed the Soul of the World chiefly in the <hi>Sun,</hi> and <hi>Heraclitus</hi> calls the <hi>Sun</hi> the <hi>Fountain</hi> of <hi>Coe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſtial</hi> light, and hence the Ancient <hi>Naturaliſt</hi> called the <hi>Sun</hi> the very heart of Heaven, ſo it ſends forth its rays on all ſides, as it were a Spirit through all things, diſtributing Life Sence and Motion to the very Univerſe, and it ſits as <hi>King</hi> in the midle of the other <hi>Pla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nets,</hi> excelling all in Light Greatneſs and Fairneſs; Enlightning all, diſtributing <hi>Vertue</hi> to them to diſpoſe Inferiour Bodys, &amp; Regulating &amp; Diſpoſing of their Motions, ſo that from thence their motions, are Dayly or Nightly Southern or Northern, Oriential or Occidenti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>al, Direct or Retrograde, and as it doth by its Light drive away all the Darkneſs of the Night, ſo alſo all Powers of Darkneſs, which we read of in <hi>Job, as ſoon as Morning ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pears they think of the Shadow of Death:</hi> Thus the <hi>Sun</hi> is the very Author of ſeaſons, from whence, Day and Year, Cold and Heat, and all other Qualities of Seaſons, as <hi>Ptolomy</hi> ſaith, when the <hi>Sun</hi> comes unto the place of any <hi>Star,</hi> it ſtirs up the power thereof, ſo as with <hi>Mars</hi> heat, with <hi>Saturn</hi> cold; and it diſpoſeth even the ſpirit and mind of man; from hence its ſaid by <hi>Homer,</hi> and approved by <hi>Ariſtole,</hi> that there are in the mind ſuch like mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions, as the <hi>Sun</hi> the Prince and Moderator of the Planets, every day bringeth to us: There<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore ſhall we then ſay, or be ſo Innocent of the Heavenly Ordinances, as to deny this great Luminary any Influence upon Humane and Mundene Affairs, or to be ſo ſtupid, as to think that when this great Light is obſcured from us, that there is nothing thereby ſignified unto Mortal Men?</p>
            <p>God Created the two great Lights, viz. the <hi>Sun</hi> and <hi>Moon</hi> for Signs and Seaſons, there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the <hi>Moon</hi> hath a certain natural Mutability, whereby ſhe eaſily Cummunicates unto us, the ſence of other <hi>Stars,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <p>Now let us come to the intended Subject, viz an Ecclipſe of the <hi>Sun,</hi> which is very great; whence we may ex<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ect as great Accidents or Effects to follow: Such a face of <hi>Heaven</hi> hath not been ſeen ſince the Creation. All the Planets are in the 9th houſe, viz, four in <hi>Cancer</hi> with <hi>Caput,</hi> and three in <hi>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>irgo: Jupiter</hi> hath great dignities in <hi>Cancer,</hi> and here is no leſs then four <hi>Planets</hi> beholds him, by a ſextil Aſpect from the ſame; Sure this muſt ſhew ſome notable Work Impending concerning <hi>Religion:</hi> But before I ſhall paſs my Judgement at length upon this vaſt Ecclipſe of the <hi>Sun;</hi> I ſhall conſider three things.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="10" facs="tcp:50004:12"/>
               <hi>Firſt,</hi> unto what <hi>Region, Kingdom, City or People,</hi> the effects of this Ecclipſe ſhall ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pertain.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Secondly,</hi> The <hi>Time</hi> when the Effects ſhall begin, and how long <hi>Time</hi> the Events of this Ecclipſe ſhall continue?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Thirdly,</hi> What events may be expected from the Ecclipſe, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>Now in regard this Ecclipſe is made in <hi>Cancer,</hi> therfore I ſhall judge its effects to fall upon <hi>Scotland, Granado, Burgundy, Holland, Zeland, Pruſia, Numidia, Africa, Bi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thinia, Calchis, Carthage, Conſtantinople, Tunis, Venice, Genoa, Lucas-piſa, Millain, Vincentia, Berne, York, St. Andrews in Scotland, Lubeck, Magdeburg, Wittenburg, Gorlick, Macedonia, Illyria, Thracia, Boſina, Albania, Oxford, Guant, India, &amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The next thing we have to conſider, is the time when this Ecclipſe will begin to Opperate, and how long the effects may continue: now in regard it is made in the ninth Angle: Therefore I judge the effects will begin about eight months from the time of the Ecclipſe, and will Continue two Years, or thereabouts, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>The <hi>Third</hi> and <hi>laſt</hi> thing is, what the effects or event of this Ecclipſe may be, as thus conſidering the ſign where this great defect of the <hi>Sun</hi> doth happen, to be one of the <hi>Cardinal</hi> ſigns, and our ſummer <hi>Solſtice:</hi> Therefore it ſignifies alteration of Air, &amp; of Offices, or Places, or Government, it likewiſe preſages a Rot or Conſumption of the vulgar ſort of People, with Rumours, Seditiors, and expectations of Wars, Deſtruction of Fiſh and Water-ſoul, great Innundations and overflowings of the Sea Banks, it likewiſe procures a Rotteneſs or Corruption in the Fruits when they are gathered, occaſioning Surfeits and Sickneſſes to ſuch as eat them, as Hydropical Diſeaſes, which may cauſe Petulent and grie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vous Mortalities, it likewiſe foreſhews the Diſeaſes of <hi>France, Naples, Spain,</hi> and <hi>En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gland,</hi> and indeed all the <hi>World;</hi> Let them that are inclined to Venery have a care, again it foreſhews Sea fights, Long and Dangerous Navigations, with ſtrang kind of Stormes and Tempeſts at Sea, and much Loſs to the Generous and Induſtrious Merchant, with thunder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Noiſes and Uproars about Religion, as well at Home as Abroad, and that by all ſorts of People from the Higheſt to the Loweſt Degree; for ſo many Planets in the 9th, in Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>junction in <hi>Cancer,</hi> and all in ſextil to <hi>Jupiter,</hi> who is exalted therein; can intimate no Leſs then Great and Fierce diſputes about Religious matters, beſides <hi>Mercurys</hi> application to the body of <hi>Mars,</hi> by a retrograde motion, who ſuddenly tranſits the degree of the Ecclipſe, ſhews that many ſtrange kind of Paper conflicts ſhall be diſperſed abroad, on purpoſe to incite Men to Quarrel, for here is a Violent Storm Impending, and Wo to thoſe People in Europe, on whom it doth fall; for as a blow with a ſtick ſtirs up the madneſs of a Dog which before lay Aſleep, ſo doth the <hi>Coeliſtial</hi> Harmony diſcloſe Virtues lying in the Ele<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, and ſtirs them up, ſtrengthneth them, and makes them manifeſt, and as I may ſay, produceth that into Act, which before was only in Power. And thus to conclude I judge, that <hi>Mars's</hi> ſudden tranſit through the Degree of the Ecclipſe, will cauſe extra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ordinary ſultry blaſts, and great heat, hot peſtilent Winds, peſtiferous and infectious Thunder, Lightnings, Whirlewinds, immeſurable Droughts, with ſtrong kind of Wea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, and variety of it; and beſides, men will be inclined to Arms, and to violate Natio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nal Leagues, Deceitful under the ſpecies of Religion; for <hi>Mars</hi> haſtes to a Sextil of <hi>Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>piter,</hi> who is a natural ſignificator thereof; beſides, <hi>Jupiter, Venus, Mars</hi> and <hi>Mercury</hi> are much debilitated in the Figure of this Ecclipſe, which much verifieth our Judgment, according to this following <hi>Aphoriſm, Notabiliter infortunantur, planeta, per retrogra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dationem, combuſtionem, peregrinationem, detrimentum, &amp; caſum: Planets are extream<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly made unfortunate when they are either Retrograde, Combuſt, Perogrine in their Detri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:50004:12"/>
or Fall.</hi> By how much the more this <hi>Aphoriſm</hi> is verified in our preſent Ecclipſe, and <hi>Vernal Ingreſs,</hi> by ſo much more the greater Evils may be expected; for in our <hi>Ver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nal Ingreſs Saturn</hi> was peregrine in his detriment and retrograde, and in the Figure of our Ecclipſe we have <hi>Mars</hi> in his fall, from hence we may expect one Miſchief upon the neck of another; and in regard this Ecclipſe doth happen in a watery ſign, <hi>viz. Cancer,</hi> the great Dignities of the <hi>Moon</hi> and <hi>Jupiter,</hi> it may denote much Contention upon Water or the Seas, about the Right of Fiſhing, either of our own Nation, the <hi>Hollander,</hi> or ſome other Northern People; as alſo, in regard <hi>Jupiter</hi> hath ſignifications of Laws, and Rights and Priviledges political, there may be doubted much Controverſie to ariſe about the Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viledges of Fiſhing; but in regard <hi>Jupiter</hi> is in ſextil to this Ecclipſe, therefore I judge the Dred will be more than the Harm, as to that, altho' there will not want ſufficient En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deavours to the contrary: but ſince <hi>Jupiter</hi> is Ruler of the Law, which is grounded upon pure Reaſon, and of it ſelf is the moſt equal and moſt juſt Law, that ever did appear in any Nation, giving every man his Right, and Tryal by his Equals; herein we allow no Abuſe: and ſo I ſhall conclude with the Poet,
<q>
                  <l>— As in great Haſte.</l>
                  <l>What makes the Golden Stars to march ſo Faſt?</l>
                  <l>What makes the Moon ſometimes to mask her Face?</l>
                  <l>The Sun alſo, as if in ſome Diſgrace?</l>
               </q>
            </p>
            <p>You that have Eyes to ſee the <hi>Stars,</hi> and ſtrange <hi>Signs in the Heavens,</hi> have more Rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon to cry out with Admiration than <hi>Dyoniſius Areopagita,</hi> who ſeeing the ſtrang Ecclipſe of the <hi>Sun</hi> and <hi>Moon</hi> at the inſtant Hour of our <hi>Saviour's Paſſion,</hi> ſaid, <hi>Aut Deus natura patitur aut mundi, machina diſſoluitur: Either the God of Nature ſuffers, or elſe the Frame of the World is diſſolved.</hi> So much from the great Eye of Heaven, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>IN the next place I ſhall proceed to Judgment upon the Scheme of the <hi>Sun's Ingreſs into Ares,</hi> commencing <hi>March</hi> the 9th, 1685. 7 hours, 42 minutes paſt noon; as may be ſeen by the following Calculation, by the <hi>Rudolphin Tables,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">
                  <p>
                     <table>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Time.</cell>
                           <cell cols="4">☉ Long.</cell>
                           <cell cols="4">☉ Apog.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Epoch.</cell>
                           <cell>s.</cell>
                           <cell>d.</cell>
                           <cell>m.</cell>
                           <cell>s.</cell>
                           <cell>s.</cell>
                           <cell>d.</cell>
                           <cell>m.</cell>
                           <cell>s.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Years 1600.</cell>
                           <cell>9.</cell>
                           <cell>20.</cell>
                           <cell>55.</cell>
                           <cell>2.</cell>
                           <cell>3.</cell>
                           <cell>5.</cell>
                           <cell>44.</cell>
                           <cell>8.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>80.</cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell>36.</cell>
                           <cell>16.</cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell>1.</cell>
                           <cell>22.</cell>
                           <cell>10.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>4.</cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell>1.</cell>
                           <cell>49.</cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell>4.</cell>
                           <cell>7.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>February</cell>
                           <cell>1.</cell>
                           <cell>28.</cell>
                           <cell>9.</cell>
                           <cell>11</cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell>10.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Dayes 8.</cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell>7.</cell>
                           <cell>53.</cell>
                           <cell>7.</cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Hours 8.</cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell>19.</cell>
                           <cell>43.</cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Min. 48.</cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell>1.</cell>
                           <cell>58.</cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Mid. lodg ☉</cell>
                           <cell>11.</cell>
                           <cell>27</cell>
                           <cell>57.</cell>
                           <cell>27</cell>
                           <cell>3.</cell>
                           <cell>7.</cell>
                           <cell>10.</cell>
                           <cell>35.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Apo. ſub.</cell>
                           <cell>3.</cell>
                           <cell>7.</cell>
                           <cell>9.</cell>
                           <cell>33.</cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Anom. Res.</cell>
                           <cell>8.</cell>
                           <cell>20.</cell>
                           <cell>46.</cell>
                           <cell>55.</cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>equa ad.</cell>
                           <cell>0.</cell>
                           <cell>2.</cell>
                           <cell>2.</cell>
                           <cell>3<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                                 <desc>•</desc>
                              </gap>.</cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>☉ place.</cell>
                           <cell>0.</cell>
                           <cell>0.</cell>
                           <cell>0.</cell>
                           <cell>0.</cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Viz.</hi> in</cell>
                           <cell>♈</cell>
                           <cell>0.</cell>
                           <cell>0.</cell>
                           <cell>0.</cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                        </row>
                     </table>
                  </p>
               </note>The Warlike Planet <hi>Mars</hi> doth make a tedious tranſit through the Sign <hi>Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gitarius</hi> this year, <hi>viz.</hi> compleat ſeven moneths; <hi>Sagitarius</hi> is the great Dig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nities of <hi>Jupiter:</hi> I hope the Souldier doth not intend to turn Preacher; <hi>Mars</hi> is all for pulling down Religion, and not for promoting it. Men of deſperate Fortune, have baſe and unlucky De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſigns. Let <hi>Mars</hi> command the needy Souldier, and <hi>Saturn</hi> the ſuperſtitious Sectary Count y<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man. Look for an End of our Troubles at Dooms Day. Oh! who can endure this factious Crew of Raſchals, who pretend <hi>Religion</hi> and <hi>Conſcience,</hi> and yet neither <hi>Fear God,</hi> nor <hi>Honour their King:</hi> But I ſhall leave them, till their <hi>Hypocriſie is detected,</hi> and the <hi>meaſure of their Iniquity at the height;</hi> but I hope we ſhall not ſuffer them long in their Deſigns, God being on our ſides.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="12" facs="tcp:50004:13"/>Here followeth the Sheme of the <hi>Sun's</hi> Ingreſs into <hi>Ares.</hi>
            </p>
            <figure>
               <head>
                  <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> ☌ ♄ ad ☍, ☉ ♀ &amp; ☿ &amp; ☿ ad <g ref="char:quadrine">□</g> ♂, &amp; ☍ ♄, ☿ ad ☌ ♀, ☉ ad <g ref="char:trine">△</g> ♂ &amp; ♂ <g ref="char:quadrine">□</g> ♄, lat. 51. 31.</head>
            </figure>
            <p>In this figure all the Angles are moveable, <hi>Jupiter</hi> Angular in the aſcending part of Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven, and <hi>Venus</hi> is in her exaltation, in conjunction with <hi>Mercury,</hi> and in ſtrong <hi>Reception</hi> with <hi>Jupiter</hi> by houſe, which ſignifications according to the rules of Art, ſhews that we ſhould enjoy both Peace and Plenty, and that the People ſhould be ſuccesful in all their Undertakings and Enterpriſes; and that they ſhould be fortunate on every ſide, Healthful in their Bodys, and that they ſhould be lovers of the law both of <hi>God</hi> and <hi>Man,</hi> and that they ſhould be deſirous to ſearch after many divine Myſteries, and that thoſe which belong to <hi>Theology</hi> and the <hi>Law</hi> ſhould be had in great and high eſteem, as Judges, Counſellers, and Men of all ſorts of Religious Orders, ſo you muſt note <hi>Jupiter</hi> ſignifies, all Judges, Counſellers, all Eccleſiaſtical Men, both Prieſt and Levites, Chancellors, Law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers, or thoſe that follow the Law, from the Higheſt to the Loweſt, all Schollars and Stud<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dents in general, and in this figure of the <hi>Suns</hi> ingreſs, he doth in part ſignify the common People, therefore their conditions ſhould be very Proſperous, Good and Happy, dureing this ſpring Quarter: but in regard the <hi>Moon</hi> is thus Afflicted by the body of diſaffected <hi>Saturn;</hi> Therefore I ſhall judge the condition of the common People to be but very Mean and Ordinary; yet the poſition of <hi>Jupiter</hi> in the aſcendant, in an aireal ſign, ſhews a plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſant Spring, with a temperate Air, &amp; very healthful to the People in general, &amp; beſides <hi>Venus</hi> being in her exaltation and in the 5th houſe; ſhews advantage unto <hi>Women,</hi> and that they ſhall generally be free from Infirmities and Miſchiefs, they ſhall love and delight in the ſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciety of their Husbands: Shall be Fruitful and eaſily conceive and bring Forth, the People ſhall generally Thrive and be Proſperous, ſhall delight themſelves in Recreations, Sports, Feaſtings, Mirth and Jollities, and all Pleaſures whatſoever; and becauſe <hi>Venus</hi> is in a
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:50004:13"/>
watry ſign, it ſhews plenty of Fiſh, and Rain in due ſeaſon; but in regard <hi>Venus</hi> applies to a ſquare of <hi>Mars</hi> in the ſecond; I judge much of this will be abated. Now in the next place I ſhall ſay ſomething concerning the poſition of <hi>Saturn</hi> in the eleventh; near the body of the <hi>Moon,</hi> ſhe being Lady of the tenth, and he within few degrees of the ſquare of <hi>Mars,</hi> who is lord of the 7th, it being the 10th from the <hi>Medium Coeli,</hi> ſuch poſitions as theſe do oftentimes deſtroy Leagues and Friendſhip between Kingdom and Kingdom; and it is much to be feared, there will not want ſtrange and ſtrong endeavours to ſet us at odds with ſome other Nation or Nations, or they with us; but the Heavens ſhew only Natural Incli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nations, not Poſitive actions. <hi>Saturn</hi> is unfortunately placed in the eleventh, which ſignifies that his cold &amp; evil Influence, will ſpread it ſelf over the whole Kingdom, under the ſign of his poſition, and that the King or chief Ruler of that Kingdom or People, ſhould remove his Habitation from one houſe to another, do little good, and yet will lay or impoſe heavy Taxes or Impoſitions upon the People, and ſhall not perform what is Juſt in their Eſteem: Now this poſition is in <hi>Virgo,</hi> therefore it relates perticularly to <hi>Lyons, Paris, Baſil, Corinthia, A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chaia, Greece, Crete, Babylon, Aſſyria, Hieruſalem, Gallia;</hi> the <hi>Dukedom</hi> of <hi>Athens,</hi> is hereby threatned with ſome kind of Penury, or Want, or Scarcity in their Proviſions: <hi>Mercury</hi> is ruler of the 9th houſe, and <hi>Venus</hi> is lady of the aſcendant, and they apply to a ſquare of <hi>Mars,</hi> and to an oppoſition of diſaffected <hi>Saturn</hi> in the 11th houſe, the 9th houſe ſignifies Religion, and all affairs appertaining to the Church, whence we may rationally conclude, this is the antecedent or forerunner of many Diviſions, high Contentions, much Diſcord, and in all probability may cauſe Wars, Bloodſhed, and commotions of Armes in many places of Europe, as <hi>Spain, Morocco, Meſina, Toledo, Mutina,</hi> for <hi>Mars</hi> in <hi>Sagitarius</hi> applies to the ſquare of <hi>Saturn,</hi> which denotes many Thefts, Murders, Rapines, Robbe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rys, and Cozening and Cheating of one another, thoſe alſo that are intruſted with Moneys or Goods of any ones, ſhall be Falſe &amp; Deceitful, and the People generally ſhall be driven to want, and be perplexed with Taxations and Tributes, and thoſe in perticular under the ſign <hi>Virgo</hi> and <hi>Sagitarius, Mars</hi> may well ſignifie the male contented Souldier, and <hi>Saturn</hi> the melancholly Country-man. And in many Countrys there will be much Heart-burning between the Martialiſt and the plain Country-man, with much Fraud, Lying, Deceit, Jug<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gling, and ſtrange Controverſies may ariſe, with high Contentions and much Diſcord, with ſharp Conflicts, managed by different Judgements or Opinions, and my reaſon is this, <hi>Venus</hi> and <hi>Mercury</hi> are in conjunction in the houſe of <hi>Jupiter,</hi> and are applying to ſquare of <hi>Mars</hi> in <hi>Sagitarius,</hi> and likewiſe to the oppoſition of <hi>Saturn,</hi> who is in the dignities of <hi>Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cury</hi> Lord of the 9th: Beſides <hi>Jupiter</hi> and <hi>Venus</hi> are in reception by houſe, <hi>Jupiter</hi> being a ſignificator of Religion, but much of this evil will be abated, for the <hi>Sun</hi> applys to a trine of <hi>Mars,</hi> the <hi>Sun</hi> being in part Lord of the 10: Therefore I judge ſome wiſe Prince will labour to take up the matter.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="14" facs="tcp:50004:14"/>IN the next place I ſhall proceed to the conſideration of the Summer Quarter, which be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gins June the 10th, 10 hours, 43 minutes paſt noon, as will be made appear by the cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culation at large.</p>
            <p>
               <table>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Time.</cell>
                     <cell cols="4">Long. ☉</cell>
                     <cell cols="4">Apog. ☉</cell>
                     <cell rows="9">This following <hi>Calculation</hi> according to all the reſt, is done by the <hi>Rudolphin Tables:</hi> the beſt extant in my opini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, let all men enjoy theirs likewiſe, &amp;c.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Epoche.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                     <cell>d.</cell>
                     <cell>m.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                     <cell>d.</cell>
                     <cell>m.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Years 1600</cell>
                     <cell>9.</cell>
                     <cell>20.</cell>
                     <cell>55.</cell>
                     <cell>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>3.</cell>
                     <cell>3.</cell>
                     <cell>5.</cell>
                     <cell>44.</cell>
                     <cell>8.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>80.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>36.</cell>
                     <cell>16.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>1.</cell>
                     <cell>22.</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>4.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>1.</cell>
                     <cell>49.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>4.</cell>
                     <cell>7.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>May</cell>
                     <cell>4.</cell>
                     <cell>28.</cell>
                     <cell>49.</cell>
                     <cell>58.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>29.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Dayes 9.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>8.</cell>
                     <cell>52.</cell>
                     <cell>15.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Hours 11.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>27.</cell>
                     <cell>6.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Min. 38.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>3<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Mid. Long. ☉</cell>
                     <cell>2.</cell>
                     <cell>29.</cell>
                     <cell>44.</cell>
                     <cell>21.</cell>
                     <cell>3.</cell>
                     <cell>7.</cell>
                     <cell>10.</cell>
                     <cell>54.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Apog. ſub.</cell>
                     <cell>3.</cell>
                     <cell>7.</cell>
                     <cell>10.</cell>
                     <cell>54.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Anom. Res.</cell>
                     <cell>11.</cell>
                     <cell>22.</cell>
                     <cell>33.</cell>
                     <cell>27.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Equa ad</cell>
                     <cell>00.</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell>15.</cell>
                     <cell>40</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>☉ place</cell>
                     <cell>♋</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
               </table>
            </p>
            <p>The FIGURE followeth, &amp;c.</p>
            <figure>
               <head>
                  <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> 
                  <g ref="char:trine">△</g> ♀ <g ref="char:trine">△</g> ☿ ad <g ref="char:trine">△</g> ☉ &amp; <g ref="char:quadrine">□</g> ♂ ☿ ad ☌ ♀ &amp; ♀ ad ☌ ☉, Lat. 51. 32. Londini, 1685.</head>
            </figure>
            <p>
               <pb n="15" facs="tcp:50004:14"/>In this figure the angles are partly fixed and partly moveable, and the Planets all indiffe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rent well ſeated <hi>Mars</hi> excepted; who is poſited in the 9th retrograd which ſhews many <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>igh diſputes ſtill concerning Religion, both at home and abroad; beſides many loſſes to the ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nerous &amp; induſtrious Merchant, from ſeveral parts beyond the Sea, as <hi>Spain, Dalmatia, Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gary, &amp;c. Aquarius</hi> aſcends, the <hi>Moon</hi> is poſited therein, and in trine of <hi>Venus</hi> and <hi>Mercury</hi> who are in conjunction with the <hi>Dragons head,</hi> in <hi>Gemini, Londons</hi> Aſcendant: The <hi>Moon</hi> is likewiſe haſting to a trine of the <hi>Sun,</hi> and <hi>Venus</hi> to his conjunction, beſides <hi>Saturn, Venus, Mercury,</hi> and the <hi>Moon</hi> are in reception with each other. The <hi>Sun</hi> is likewiſe going to a ſextile of <hi>Saturn,</hi> which in my opinion portends nothing but Peace and Tranquility to us, eſpecially to London, the Motropolitan City of <hi>England,</hi> yet notwithſtanding there will be ſtrange kind of endeavours uſed to ſet us at varience amongſt our ſelves, &amp; that by a factious crew of Villains, who make it their buſineſs to diſturb and oppoſe the Government, as doth appear by the figure, for no ſooner then the <hi>Moon</hi> is parted from the trine of the <hi>Sun,</hi> but ſhe meets with the ſquare of <hi>Mars,</hi> who oppoſeth <hi>Gemini.</hi> But <hi>agunt non cogunt,</hi> the heavens incline, and not compel, therefore let us pray to God, to direct the hearts of all thoſe which ſit at the ſtern of Government, and let us ſit down in peace and be contented with what God hath given us; for we injoy that which many Nations would be glad to ſee, for that tripple conjunction of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter</hi> in <hi>Leo,</hi> doth cauſe tranquilitys to us in England, when many other Nations do labour under its dire effects. Thus goes fortunes wheele about, while one is a getting up, another is going down, ſome are for one intereſt and ſome for another. <hi>Spain</hi> I pitty thy condition, for thou who waſt formerly the miſtreſs of the World, art now become Sick and Faint, and thy relief is weak; ſeek out for a <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ood Phyſician in time, for thy ſtrength decays, and hath done ever ſince the year 1683. a time freſh in memory, &amp;c. Here are ſeveral myſteries in this figure, if I durſt unfold them; but for ſear of giving an offence I ſhall paſs them by, and give you an account of what diſeaſes are moſt likely to happen this Quarter, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>Thus rhe <hi>Moon</hi> is lady of the ſix, and poſited in the aſcendant in <hi>Aquary,</hi> which foreſhews <hi>Surfeits, Rheume</hi> in the <hi>Eyes, Worms, Rotten Coughs, Convu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>ion, Dropſies</hi> in the <hi>Legs, Meaſles,</hi> and many more cold watery <hi>Humours,</hi> which hath infected the Blood, and in all probability the <hi>Small-Pox,</hi> becauſe the <hi>Moon</hi> applies to a ſquare of <hi>Mars</hi> in <hi>Sagitarius;</hi> hold, I had almoſt forgot <hi>Jupiter</hi> in <hi>Libra,</hi> who is lord of the 10th, 11th, &amp; Intercepted ſign in the aſcendant, which ſhews great love &amp; unity between the Superiours &amp; Commons of this land, yet ſtill complaint for the want of trade &amp; monys and that not only by the common People, but by thoſe of the higheſt Degree and Quality, as may be ſeen by <hi>Cauda</hi> in the 11: which in my opinion cauſeth great expence and loſs of Eſtate, to thoſe belonging to the Church or Church Livings, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="16" facs="tcp:50004:15"/>IN the next place I ſhall give you ſome ſmall judgement upon the figure of the <hi>Suns</hi> ente<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rance into <hi>Libra,</hi> which commences this year September the 12th, 2 houres, 31 minutes paſt noon, as the following Calculation doth expreſs, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>
               <table>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Time.</cell>
                     <cell cols="4">Long. ☉</cell>
                     <cell cols="4">Apog. ☉</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Epoch.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                     <cell>d.</cell>
                     <cell>m.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                     <cell>d.</cell>
                     <cell>m.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Years 1600.</cell>
                     <cell>9.</cell>
                     <cell>20.</cell>
                     <cell>55.</cell>
                     <cell>2.</cell>
                     <cell>3.</cell>
                     <cell>5.</cell>
                     <cell>44.</cell>
                     <cell>8.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>80.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>36.</cell>
                     <cell>16.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>1.</cell>
                     <cell>22.</cell>
                     <cell>10.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>4.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>1.</cell>
                     <cell>49.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>4.</cell>
                     <cell>7.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Auguſt</cell>
                     <cell>7.</cell>
                     <cell>29.</cell>
                     <cell>30.</cell>
                     <cell>44</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>41.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Dayes 11.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>10.</cell>
                     <cell>50.</cell>
                     <cell>32.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Hours 3.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>7.</cell>
                     <cell>24.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Min. 17.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>42.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Mid long ☉</cell>
                     <cell>6.</cell>
                     <cell>2.</cell>
                     <cell>2.</cell>
                     <cell>50.</cell>
                     <cell>3.</cell>
                     <cell>7.</cell>
                     <cell>11.</cell>
                     <cell>6.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Apo. ſub.</cell>
                     <cell>3.</cell>
                     <cell>7.</cell>
                     <cell>11.</cell>
                     <cell>6.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Anom. Res.</cell>
                     <cell>2.</cell>
                     <cell>24.</cell>
                     <cell>51.</cell>
                     <cell>41.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>equa ſub.</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                     <cell>2.</cell>
                     <cell>2.</cell>
                     <cell>50.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>☉ place.</cell>
                     <cell>6.</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>Viz.</hi> in</cell>
                     <cell>♎</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
               </table>
            </p>
            <p>The FIGURE followeth.</p>
            <figure>
               <head>
                  <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> ⚹ ♄ ad <g ref="char:quadrine">□</g> ♀ ♃ ☿ &amp; ⚹ ☉, ☿ ☌ ♃ ♀ ad ☌ ♃ ☉ ad <g ref="char:quadrine">□</g> ♂, &amp; ♀ ad ☌ ♀ lat. 51 32, Londi.</head>
            </figure>
            <p>
               <pb n="17" facs="tcp:50004:15"/>In this ſcheme of the <hi>Suns</hi> ingreſs into <hi>Libra, Saturn</hi> and <hi>Mars</hi> rules the firſt and tenth, and <hi>Venus</hi> and the <hi>Moon,</hi> the 4th and 7th: All the planets are above the Earth, and the <hi>Moon</hi> and <hi>Venus</hi> are in their own houſes: <hi>Mars</hi> in his exaltation in the ſign aſcen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding, and <hi>Saturn</hi> lord thereof in <hi>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>irgo,</hi> in the 8th; in reception with his diſpoſer; beſides here are no leſs then three planets in conjunction in <hi>Libra,</hi> with part of fortune in the 9th, viz. <hi>Jupiter, Venus,</hi> and <hi>Mercury,</hi> and the <hi>Moon</hi> applying to a ſquare of them all: This Poſition ſhews ſome high diſpute concerning Religion, which now is in its Zenith of Power and Glory; and doth Flouriſh like a flouriſhing Bough, which never fadeth; and now, and not till now, our Land begins to Thrive and Proſper after many a hot diſpute. And now the People begin to take delight in themſelves, and Love and Obey their Superiours. It likewiſe ſhews great Profit and Advantage to the Induſtrious Merchant, from ſeveral parts beyond the Seas; and probable the arrival of ſome <hi>Embaſſodour</hi> from forreign parts, or at leaſtwiſe great news from the remote parts, &amp;c. Beſides the people ſhould thrive, by re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moveing from on Place or Houſe to another; and men ſhould love and delight in the Law both of God and Man, Moral and Divine; and ſhould eſteem of all good learning, and ſtrive to be vertuous, they ſhould likewiſe be deſirous of each others Society, and delight in all honeſt and good Learning, and apply their minds to find out hidden Secrets and Myſte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries, and ſhould perform mony long Journeys with ſafety and pleaſure, &amp;c. This poſition doth likewiſe ſhew a healthfull Air, with great profit by ſmall Cattle, and Servants, who will prove true and truſty to their Maſters: Beſides the <hi>Moon</hi> in the 7th, ſhews that ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny Marriages ſhould be performed this Quarter, and thoſe very Eminent; and Men ſhould be fortunate in Women, and Gain and Profit much by them: But the lord of the aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cendant in the 8th, who is old <hi>Saturn;</hi> ſhews that many antient People ſhall make their exit out of the World this Quarter. And the ſquare of the <hi>Sun</hi> to <hi>Mars</hi> who is lord of the 10th, doth ſhew the death of ſome great martial Perſon, who lives in great ſplendor, but cannot deny <hi>Death</hi> when he comes. For <hi>Sol</hi> is lord of the 8th, and is poſited therein and in his fall: Therefore <hi>Mars</hi> lay by thy ſword, and yeild to that Meſſenger, for it is appointed all men once muſt Die, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>And thus I proceed to the judgement of the Winter Quarter, which happens <hi>Decem.</hi> the 10th, 14 hours, 11 minutes paſt Noon, as it is explained by this following Calcula<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>tion.</p>
            <p>
               <table>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Time.</cell>
                     <cell cols="4">Long. ☉</cell>
                     <cell cols="4">Apog. ☉</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Epoch.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                     <cell>d.</cell>
                     <cell>m.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                     <cell>d.</cell>
                     <cell>m.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Years 1600.</cell>
                     <cell>9.</cell>
                     <cell>20.</cell>
                     <cell>55.</cell>
                     <cell>2.</cell>
                     <cell>3.</cell>
                     <cell>5.</cell>
                     <cell>44.</cell>
                     <cell>8.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>80.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>36.</cell>
                     <cell>16.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>1.</cell>
                     <cell>22.</cell>
                     <cell>10.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>4.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>1.</cell>
                     <cell>49.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>4.</cell>
                     <cell>7.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Novemb.</cell>
                     <cell>10.</cell>
                     <cell>29.</cell>
                     <cell>12.</cell>
                     <cell>22.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>56.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Dayes 9.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>8.</cell>
                     <cell>52.</cell>
                     <cell>15.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Hours 15.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>36.</cell>
                     <cell>57.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Min. 6.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>15.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Mid. long ☉</cell>
                     <cell>9.</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                     <cell>15.</cell>
                     <cell>17.</cell>
                     <cell>3.</cell>
                     <cell>7.</cell>
                     <cell>11.</cell>
                     <cell>21.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Apo. ſub.</cell>
                     <cell>3.</cell>
                     <cell>7.</cell>
                     <cell>11.</cell>
                     <cell>21.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Anom. Res.</cell>
                     <cell>5.</cell>
                     <cell>23.</cell>
                     <cell>3.</cell>
                     <cell>56.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>equa ſub.</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                     <cell>15.</cell>
                     <cell>17.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>☉ place.</cell>
                     <cell>9.</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>Viz.</hi> in</cell>
                     <cell>♑</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                  </row>
               </table>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb n="18" facs="tcp:50004:16"/>The FIGURE followeth.</p>
            <figure>
               <head>
                  <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> 
                  <g ref="char:trine">△</g> ♀, ad ⚹ ☉ &amp; <g ref="char:trine">△</g> ♂, ☉ <g ref="char:quadrine">□</g> ♄ ☿ ⚹ ♂, &amp; <g ref="char:quadrine">□</g> ♄ ♀ ad <g ref="char:quadrine">□</g> ♃ ☿ ⚹, Lat. 51. 3<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>. Londini,</head>
            </figure>
            <p>The angles of this figure are all common, and all the Planets are Sub<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>errane, and <hi>Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cury</hi> is lord of the two principle angles, viz, the Aſcendant and Mid-heaven, and <hi>Jupiter</hi> is ruler of the north and weſt Angles. <hi>Saturn</hi> is unfortunately placed in the aſcendant, and in ſquare of the <hi>Sun</hi> and <hi>Mercury</hi> lord thereof, this gives <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ay for the conjunction of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter</hi> to ſpread its effects all over the univerſe, and beſides here are many plotting counſells on foot, ſtill contriveing how and which way they may bring their wicked deſigns to paſs, for <hi>Mercury</hi> is lord of the aſcendant, and the <hi>Sun</hi> of the 12th, and they are ſeperateting from the ſquare of diſaffected <hi>Saturn,</hi> who is naturally evil and corrupt, Self ended, Covetous, and Malitious, one who hath been an underground worker this many years, in contriveing damned Plots, to the ruin and ſubvertion of Nations: But ſince <hi>Mercury</hi> is in ſextil to <hi>Mars,</hi> and haſts to a ſextil of <hi>Jupiter,</hi> who is in ſtrong reception with <hi>Mars</hi> by houſe, and becauſe the <hi>Sun</hi> haſts to a trine of <hi>Mars</hi> &amp; <hi>Jupiter,</hi> and <hi>Mars</hi> likewiſe is applying to a trine of <hi>Jupiter</hi> himſelf, &amp; the <hi>Moon</hi> defluxing from a trine of <hi>Venus,</hi> &amp; applying to a ſextil of the <hi>Sun,</hi> and a trine of <hi>Mars,</hi> and aſextil of <hi>Mercury.</hi> Therefore I judge that many will la<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bour to ſecure themſelves and their friends too, as well the <hi>Martialiſt,</hi> as the <hi>Gown-man.</hi> Therefore look to it Preacher, ſtand faſt Souldiers, ſince you are about to unite, and maintain your principals, and have at their ſeminaries by gheſs, for <hi>Venus</hi> goes to a ſquare of <hi>Jupi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter,</hi> and <hi>Mars</hi> to an oppoſition of <hi>Saturn,</hi> &amp;c. The <hi>Moon</hi> is fortunate in the ſecond, Therefore ſhe promiſeth that men ſhall gain and profit, and abound in riches, haveing plenty of all things, but <hi>Saturn</hi> in the aſcendant who is lord of the 6th, denotes miſcheif and trou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles to the people in their proper perſons, alſo many ſtrange infirmities and vexations, to thoſe under the ſigns <hi>Virgo</hi> and <hi>Piſces,</hi> as you may read in Mr. <hi>Lillys Chriſtian Aſtrology,</hi> page the 96 and 99, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="19" facs="tcp:50004:16"/>In the next place, I ſhall give you an account of the Lunations Ecclipſed this Year, as thus, once the <hi>Sun</hi> and twice the <hi>Moon,</hi> the firſt will be of the <hi>Moon,</hi> on the ſixth day of June, at ſix at night <hi>Inviſible,</hi> it falls in the laſt face of <hi>Sagitarius,</hi> it ſignifies a Plague, Conſumption, and great evills to afflict mankind more then ordinary. The ſecond will be an ecclipſe of the <hi>Sun,</hi> on June the 21th at eight a clock at night, <hi>Inviſible,</hi> it happens in the firſt face of <hi>Cancer,</hi> this ſignifies a diſturbed Air, and ſtrange kind of weather, it like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe enclines men to Arms, and to violate Nationall Leagues, Deceitfully under the ſpecies of Religion. The third and laſt is an ecclipſe of the <hi>Moon,</hi> which falls on the 30th of Novem. at eleven at night, it will be <hi>Viſible</hi> totall and centrall, it is celibrated in the ſecond face of <hi>Gemini,</hi> London's aſcendant, it ſtirs up Diſſenſions, Strifes, Seditions amongſt thoſe we call Prieſts, and all manner of Merchants and Mechanicks of every order, or a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny quality that is amongſt them, deadly hatred, contempt of Laws, neglect of Piety and holy Dutys doth alſo follow, with much Piracy at ſea, and Murders, many fruitleſs Treatys and many turbulent Petitions, preſented by the people to their Superiours. All theſe things will happen to thoſe places under the ſigns <hi>Gemini, Cancer,</hi> and <hi>Sagitarius,</hi> as <hi>Spain, Holland, Scotland, Hungary, Celtica, Thirronia, Narbon, Colonia, Granado, Burgun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy, Zeland, Venice, Genoa, York, Flanders, Brabant, Sardinia, Arminia, Bruges, Hasford, Montz; London</hi> thou mayſt feel a little too, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>IN the next place I ſhall proceed to the conſideration of the figure of the <hi>Suns</hi> ingreſs into <hi>Aries,</hi> which happens this year, march the 9th, 13 hours, 39 minutes paſt noon, as it doth appear by the calculation at large, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>
               <table>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Time.</cell>
                     <cell cols="4">Long ☉</cell>
                     <cell cols="4">Apog. ☉</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Epoche.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                     <cell>d.</cell>
                     <cell>m.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                     <cell>d.</cell>
                     <cell>m.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Years 1600</cell>
                     <cell>9.</cell>
                     <cell>20.</cell>
                     <cell>55.</cell>
                     <cell>23-</cell>
                     <cell>3.</cell>
                     <cell>5.</cell>
                     <cell>44.</cell>
                     <cell>8.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>80.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>36.</cell>
                     <cell>16.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>1.</cell>
                     <cell>22.</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>5.</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>29</cell>
                     <cell>47.</cell>
                     <cell>29.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>5.</cell>
                     <cell>8.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Febr</cell>
                     <cell>1.</cell>
                     <cell>28.</cell>
                     <cell>9.</cell>
                     <cell>11.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>1.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Dayes 8.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>7.</cell>
                     <cell>5.</cell>
                     <cell>7.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Hours 14.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>34.</cell>
                     <cell>20.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Min. 41.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>41.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Mid. Long ☉.</cell>
                     <cell>11.</cell>
                     <cell>27.</cell>
                     <cell>57.</cell>
                     <cell>27.</cell>
                     <cell>3.</cell>
                     <cell>7.</cell>
                     <cell>11.</cell>
                     <cell>3<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Apog. ſub.</cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>7.</cell>
                     <cell>11.</cell>
                     <cell>36.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Anom. Res.</cell>
                     <cell>8.</cell>
                     <cell>20.</cell>
                     <cell>45.</cell>
                     <cell>51.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Equa ad</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell>02</cell>
                     <cell>02.</cell>
                     <cell>3<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>☉ place.</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>Viz.</hi> 1<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>♈</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                  </row>
               </table>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb n="20" facs="tcp:50004:17"/>The FIGURE followeth, &amp;c.</p>
            <figure>
               <head>March the 10th, 39 paſt 1 in the morni<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>g 1686, &amp;c. <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> ⚹ ☉, <g ref="char:quadrine">□</g> ♀ &amp; ad ☉ ♂ lat. 51 52,</head>
            </figure>
            <p>In this figure of the <hi>Suns</hi> ingreſs into <hi>Ares,</hi> the Angles are moveable &amp; common, <hi>Jupiter</hi> and <hi>Venus</hi> rules the firſt and tenth, and <hi>Mars</hi> &amp; <hi>Mercury</hi> rules the fourth and ſeventh. The <hi>Moon</hi> ſeperates from a ſextil of the <hi>Sun,</hi> and a ſquare of <hi>Venus,</hi> and haſts to a ſquare of <hi>Mars,</hi> who is poſited in <hi>Taurus</hi> his detriment, the <hi>Moon</hi> ſignifies the common people in general, and <hi>Venus</hi> women both Noble and Ignoble, <hi>Mars</hi> ſouldiers, <hi>Jupiter</hi> divinity and law and in part the common people, being he is lord of the aſcendant. No<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> in regard the <hi>Moon</hi> is ſo much afflicted by the malevolent ſquare of <hi>Mars,</hi> who applies to an oppoſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of <hi>Jupiter</hi> in the 11th retrograd, therefore I conceive much loſs and damage to hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pen to Perſons of Dignity and Renown, or ſuch as are imployed in place of great truſt, as well thoſe belonging to the Clergy and Law, as the common People: And ſince theſe malevolent configurations are made from fixed ſigns. I judge theſe wicked deſigns hath been a long time a contriving, for like as a match doth lye and ſmother a long time before it cometh to the Train, even ſo the ſparks of envy lye a long time in the hearts of evil and wicked Perſons, before they break forth, &amp;c. and beſides this poſition threatens our greater ſort of Cattle, with ſome kind of mortality, which may ſuppreſs and deſtroy many of them, &amp;c. <hi>Mercury</hi> is lord of the 9th, and in ſextil of <hi>Venus,</hi> and <hi>Mars</hi> haſts to a trine of <hi>Jupiter,</hi> and an oppoſition of <hi>Saturn, Mercury</hi> is poor and peregrine, yet nimble and full of Eloquence from him all ingenious and learned Perſons were named. The <hi>Sun</hi> ſignifies Kings, Princes, and Magiſtrates, and he in oppoſition of diſaffed <hi>Saturn</hi> in the 9th, who ſignifies Popes, Monks, Fryars, Jeſuits, and all Jewiſh ceremonys; this ſhews ſome notable and high diſpute, amongſt the grandees of Europe; in and about Religion or Religious matters, and many of thoſe belonging to the long <hi>Robe,</hi> found guilty of what is layed to their charge;
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:50004:17"/>
yet how fair &amp; ſeemingly things ſeem to be carried on, for friendſhip and mutual agreement, and yet how many fraudulent deſigns are in agitation, near theſe times; Articles, Cove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants &amp; Leagues, controverted in thoſe Countrys, eſpecially ſubject unto thoſe ſigns <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Mars</hi> are in, from hence no good can be expected, becauſe both theſe planets are of Evil ſignification to mankind. <hi>Saturn</hi> denotes Scarcity, Poverty, Penury, Wants, and Mundene Impoveriſhments in the common Mans purſe, as well as in his Superiours. likewiſe many great loſſes to the Generous and Induſtrious Merchants, occaſioned by vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>olent ſtorms and tempeſts, and the retrogradation of <hi>Jupiter</hi> in the 11th, in that treacherous ſign <hi>Scorpio,</hi> acquaints great Princes of much falſeneſs in their allies, much treachery in ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny of their pretended friends, Servants, Counſellours, Officers in command, both by Sea and Land, beſides theſe poſitions ſignifie many needleſs conſultations and debates, alſo contradictory Counſells and Diſputes, whence little or nothing of good can be expected to the Publique, as will appear in a ſhort time, for turbulent Spirits will ſhew themſelves active to purpoſe, and that in <hi>Ireland, Sweedland, Polonia, Ruſſia, Nants, Perſia, Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bylon, Hieruſalem, Lyons, Paris, Baſil, Greece, Creet,</hi> and <hi>Aſſiria. Venus</hi> is lady of the 10th, and ſhe applies to the body of <hi>Mars</hi> in <hi>Taurus</hi> her own houſe, but before ſhe comes to a partial conjunction, ſhe becomes retrograd.</p>
            <q>
               <l>Then let none truſt Fortune, but follow reaſon,</l>
               <l>For oftentimes we ſee in truſt is Treaſon,</l>
               <l>For where the People Hate, and where the Prince Frown,</l>
               <l>What Might builds up Diſcention ſoon pulls down.</l>
            </q>
            <p>In the next place I ſhall conſider what Diſeaſes are moſt likely to happen this half Year, and ſo I ſhall conclude. Thus conſidering the Cuſp of the 6th, to be an arial ſign, and <hi>Mercury</hi> lord therof, poſited in <hi>Piſces</hi> a watry ſign, and <hi>Jupiter</hi> lord of the aſcendant, being poſited in a watry ſign. Therefore I judge that the Diſeaſes this half year, will proceed from Blood and Water, which may cauſe the Meaſles, Small-pox, Paines in the Head, with Weakneſs in the Leggs and Feet, Gonorrhea, with many violent diſtempers in the Veins, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="22" facs="tcp:50004:18"/>In the next place I ſhall proceed to the conſideration of the Autumnal half year, com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>menceing ſeptem. the 12th, 1686. 8 hours, 24 minutes paſt noon, as it doth appear by this following calculation at large, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>
               <table>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Time.</cell>
                     <cell cols="4">Long. ☉</cell>
                     <cell cols="4">Apog. ☉</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Epoche.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                     <cell>d.</cell>
                     <cell>m.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                     <cell>d.</cell>
                     <cell>m.</cell>
                     <cell>s.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Years 1600</cell>
                     <cell>9.</cell>
                     <cell>20.</cell>
                     <cell>55.</cell>
                     <cell>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>3.</cell>
                     <cell>3.</cell>
                     <cell>5.</cell>
                     <cell>44.</cell>
                     <cell>8.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>80.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>36.</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>1.</cell>
                     <cell>22.</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>5.</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                     <cell>29</cell>
                     <cell>47.</cell>
                     <cell>29..</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>5.</cell>
                     <cell>8.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Auguſt</cell>
                     <cell>7.</cell>
                     <cell>29.</cell>
                     <cell>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>0.</cell>
                     <cell>11.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>41.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Dayes 9.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>10.</cell>
                     <cell>50.</cell>
                     <cell>32.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Hours 9.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>22.</cell>
                     <cell>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Min. 10.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>5.</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Mid. Long. ☉.</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>2.</cell>
                     <cell>3.</cell>
                     <cell>0.</cell>
                     <cell>3.</cell>
                     <cell>7.</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                     <cell>7.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Apog. ſub.</cell>
                     <cell>3.</cell>
                     <cell>7.</cell>
                     <cell>12.</cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Anom. Res.</cell>
                     <cell>2.</cell>
                     <cell>24.</cell>
                     <cell>50.</cell>
                     <cell>53.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Equa ad</cell>
                     <cell>00.</cell>
                     <cell>02.</cell>
                     <cell>02.</cell>
                     <cell>33.</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>☉ place</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>Viz.</hi> in</cell>
                     <cell>♎</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                  </row>
               </table>
            </p>
            <p>The FIGURE followeth, &amp;c.</p>
            <figure>
               <head>
                  <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> 
                  <g ref="char:trine">△</g> ♀, ⚹ ☉ ad ⚹ ♄ &amp; <g ref="char:trine">△</g> ♂, ♀ <g ref="char:trine">△</g> ♃ ☉ ad ☌ ♄, ☿ ad ☌ ☉ &amp; ☌ ♄, &amp; ♂ ad <g ref="char:trine">△</g> ♃, September the 12<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>h, 8 hours, 24 mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nutes paſt noon, 1686.</head>
            </figure>
            <p>
               <pb n="23" facs="tcp:50004:18"/>The Angles of this figure are partly fixed and partly common, and all the Planets ſubteranean, <hi>Mercury</hi> and <hi>Saturn</hi> rules the firſt and tenth, and the <hi>Sun</hi> and <hi>Jupiter</hi> the fou<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>th and ſeventh, the City ſign aſcends, let the figure be ſet by any tables extent, bold daring <hi>Mars</hi> is in ſquare to the ſame, and he is lord of the 12th; what more miſchievous Plots a contriving ſtill againſt our Metropolitan City? Oh how uncertain and unſtable the na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tionall affairs of this World at preſent are? eſpecially thoſe either of active, or rich Princes, any perſon though of mean capacity, may perceive by the application of the <hi>Sun</hi> and <hi>Mercury</hi> to the body of <hi>Saturn,</hi> the actions and conſultations of Princes will be very eminent and conſiderable this half year; which may cauſe ſome fude amongſt them, and in all probability incite them to attempts of War; for <hi>Mars</hi> his ſudden application to the ſextil of <hi>Jupiter</hi> in <hi>Scorpio,</hi> ſhews ſome treacherous deſigns in counſells, which can in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>timate no leſs, and beſides <hi>Mars</hi> applies to the body of <hi>Saturn,</hi> a notable con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>junction in earneſt, it is of ill influence upon all Perſons and Places concerned therein; as <hi>Auſtria, Livonia, Caſpia, Thuſia, Seres, Sundgavia, Baſtrina, Delphinat, Alſatia, Sabandia, Lisbone, Cajetam, Spiers, Franckfoord, Lau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dem, France, Germany, Burgundy, Denmark, Paleſtine, Polonia, Flo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rence, Sweeden</hi> and <hi>England,</hi> By this poſition the winds ſhould blow high, threatning many loſſes, ſome by Pyracy, others by Shipwracks, and the high wayes of our Nation peſtered with Theeves, from which occaſions, we here of ſtrange Murthers, and unuſual Robberys, out of houſes, in houſes in the weſtern and northern Roads of England, with fearfull Diviſions, and many Tumults, much Tergiverſation in Counſells, much Treaſon, high rant<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Pamphlets, diſperſing the ſeeds of Treaſon; inviting to the Murther of Magiſtrates, Plotting, and eminent Martial-men found guilty thereof, yet the ſtate of England ſtands firm, and our Foundation reſts firm unſhaken, but have we our ſhare in ſad news or unwellcome Intelligence? Between this and the cloſe of the Year, the Auſt<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ian Cedars ſhake, ſome Princes begin to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cline. <hi>Saturn</hi> is entered into <hi>Libra,</hi> he entred <hi>Libra</hi> too in 1657. at which time the Emperour of Germany departed this life, a ſober Prince and of grear Majeſty. Therefore I judge the affliction of <hi>Saturn</hi> this year 1686. doth foreſhew that ſome Honourable Perſon of the <hi>Auſtrian Blood,</hi> may in the cir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuit of the year end his days, near upon that tract of land, or in that country where even he dyed, &amp;c. The <hi>Moon</hi> is in ſextil of the <hi>Sun,</hi> and adds to a ſextil of <hi>Saturn,</hi> and <hi>Caput</hi> is near the cuſp of the aſcendant, and <hi>Mercury</hi> lord thereof applies to the body of <hi>Saturn,</hi> who receives him like a noble ſoul in his exal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tation. <hi>Saturn</hi> is lord of the 10th, ſuch ſignifications as theſe ſhews great unity and love Between the Superiours and Commons of this Land, yet there is much repining amongſt the common and vulgar ſort of People, for ſuch things
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:50004:19"/>
as are neceſſary for their ſupportment, for <hi>Mercury</hi> is retrograd and the <hi>Moon</hi> is near <hi>Cauda Draconis,</hi> and is haſting to an oppoſition of the degrees aſcending, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>Now the next thing to be conſidered is what diſeaſes are likely to happen this half year, as thus, <hi>Libra</hi> deſending on the 6th, and <hi>Venus</hi> lady thereof poſited in <hi>Leo,</hi> intimates diſeaſes of Blood and Choller, and <hi>Jupiter</hi> in the 6th in <hi>Scor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pio</hi> a watry ſign, ſhews diſeaſes of Blood and Flegme, and <hi>Saturn</hi> the <hi>Sun</hi> and <hi>Mercury</hi> in the ſign of the 6th, ſhews diſeaſes of Blood and Melancholly, thus all things being conſidered and well weighed in the ballance of reaſon, I judge that the diſeaſes of this half year will be of compound humours, yet Blood will moſt abound, and that to be much corrupted and diſordered, whence may ariſe many ſtrange kind of Agues and Feavours, likewiſe Dropſies, Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſumption ſtoppage of Urine, weakneſs in the Reins, and afflictions in the Longs, whence many ſtrange kind of Coughs proceed, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>In the next place I ſhall give you an account of the luminaries ecclipſed this year; and ſo I ſhall conclude, as thus, there is but one ecclipſe only, and that is of the <hi>Moon,</hi> and it falls on the 19th of november, at eleven a clock at night, and is well worthy the obſervation of the Ingenious Sons of Urania, it hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pens in the firſt face of the <hi>Coeliſtial-Twinns,</hi> near <hi>Occulus Tauri,</hi> it begins in the 10th houſe, and ends in the 9th, <hi>Mercury</hi> and <hi>Jupiter</hi> beſiege the <hi>Sun,</hi> and the ecclipſed <hi>Moon</hi> is oppoſed by them all, and that from as violent fixed Stars as ſhe her ſelf is near; which according to the Doctrine of the Antients, threaten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth Incurſions and Rapines of Enemys, likewiſe the death of ſome Noble and Illu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrious Woman, beſides many ſolicitations of Private and Publique things, if not frequent motion of Armys in many places of <hi>Europe,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <p>So much for predictions upon the Annual revolutions of the <hi>Sun,</hi> and Ecclipſes only.</p>
            <p>In the next place I ſhall give you a word or two concerning that tripple Conjunction of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter,</hi> which happened 1682. and 1683. in that regal ſign <hi>Leo,</hi> it being the great dignitys of the <hi>Sun</hi> and <hi>Jupiter,</hi> it was uſher<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed in by two new Stars which appeared in 1680. and 1682. juſt ſuch a one as the firſt was ſeen before our Saviours Birth, at which time there was a great conjunction of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter</hi> in <hi>Piſces,</hi> as it doth appear by the <hi>Rudolphin</hi> Tables: it was in <hi>Caeſar Auguſtus</hi> his Reign, in whoſe time the <hi>Sybillians</hi> were very expert in the knowledge of this Noble and Heavenly Science; for one <hi>Sybillia Triburtina</hi> told the Emperour, <q>that it pointed out a Child born of a Virgin, which ſhould be greater then he, therefore ſhe exhorted him to wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip him, &amp;c.</q>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb n="25" facs="tcp:50004:19"/>Hiſtories, Ancient Writers, and Common Experience in former Ages teſtifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth unto us, that theſe Signs in the Heaven, as appearance of Comets and Meetings of the Superiour Stars are the aſſured fore-runners of the ſterility of the Earth, Peſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lence, Famine, War, alterations of Kingdoms, States and Empires, Laws and Cuſtoms, Winds, Earthquakes, Inundations, extream Heat and Drought, grie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vous Diſeaſes and Infirmities, and ſuch like horrid Evils, likewiſe Anxiety and Trouble, Treaſons, Treacheries, and the Death of Kings, Nobles, Princes, Em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perours and Powers; who knows but that theſe unuſual Apparitions and Meetings of the Superiour Stars may be the fore-runners of the Cataſtrophe of <hi>Rome,</hi> for it can pretend nothing but Tranquility to us in <hi>England,</hi> ſince it is in <hi>Trine</hi> to <hi>Aries</hi> our Aſcendant; yet violent and raging Diſeaſes muſt certainly be expected, from which I pray <hi>Good Lord deliver us,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <p>The Configurations of thoſe Glorious Celeſtial Bodies, are like Seeds ſcattered in the vaſt Field of Time; and if ſo, 'tis a wonder if ſome of them do not appear and grow up to Maturity; for moſt Men do know, and will readily acknowledge, Superiours do influence and govern Inferiours; <hi>and there is an appointed time and ſea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon for every thing under the Sun:</hi> Nay, it were Ridiculous for us to think that the Load-ſtone ſhould have ſo much affinity with the Iron, and the Stars of Heaven ſhould have no affinity with their fellow Nature below; for even as the Iron receives the Virtue of the Load-ſtone, ſo doth our Bodies receive the Good and Evil Influ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ence of thoſe Celeſtial and Heavenly Meſſengers: Therefore I conceive the genu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ine ſenſe of this preſent Conjunction is, That Mens Intentions and Actions will gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rally and wholly incline to ſettle or unſettle the Laws and Conſtitutions, Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtoms and Priviledges of Nations; for the Conjunctional Returns of the Superi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>our Planets into the Fiery Trigon, have always been attended with many notable and memorable Changes both in Church and State, and very great Actions and Alterations in Kingdoms and Countries, almoſt Univerſally all over the World: The firſt Reſtitution of this Trigon, after the Creation of the World, was in the days of <hi>Enoch,</hi> who walked with God, and lived 365 years, for which ſpace of time was the Church of God preſerved: The ſecond at the Univerſal Deluge, at which time the whole World was deſtroyed. Then <hi>Noah</hi> was a Preſerver of the Church of God in the Ark: The third in the time of <hi>Moſes,</hi> and the Children of <hi>Iſrael,</hi> at which time the People of God were delivered from the <hi>Egyptian</hi> Slavery: The fourth in the Monarchy of the <hi>Medes</hi> and <hi>Solomon</hi>'s Glory, who builded a Temple for the People of God: The fifth in our Bleſſed Saviours time, and the <hi>Roman</hi> Empire, <hi>Caeſar Auguſtus,</hi> in whoſe Days and Reign our Saviour Chriſt was born, who came upon the Earth to Redeem Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kind: The ſixth Return was in the time of <hi>Charles</hi> the Great, who cauſed a flou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſhing ſtate of the Church of God: And now this ſeventh Return into the Fiery Trigon, which is a Sabattical Return, hath a moſt ſingular Myſtery in it, and pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſeth ſomething of more ſignal moment to the World, than other Conjunctions do, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Signs afflicted by the Infortunes in this Conjunction are <hi>Leo, Virgo,</hi> and <hi>Libra,</hi> the oppoſite Sign to the Conjunction is <hi>Aquarius,</hi> and thoſe Signs in ſquare are <hi>Taurus</hi> and <hi>Scorpio:</hi> The Sign of the Conjunction deſigneth <hi>Rome, Italy, Sicily, Bohemia, Turky, Togata, Apalie, Emilia, Sabina, Phenicia, Chaldea, Orchinia, Dalmatia, Syracuſa, Rouvenna, Cremona, Confluant, Prague, Liniz, Crinifium,</hi>
               <pb n="26" facs="tcp:50004:20"/>
wherein ſhall be much Diſſolation, Famine, Tumults, and Uproars, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> this Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>junction will afford much Diſtraction, Diſcontent, Sorrow, Commotions of Armies, Wars, Blood-ſhed, and Pennury to many more Nations and Cities, which are un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der the oppoſite Sign <hi>Aquarius,</hi> as <hi>Amazonia, Sarmatia, Tartary, Valachia, Muſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>covia, Sweedeland, Weſtphalia, Moſellpiomont, Bavaria, Ethiopia, Oxiana, Sogdiana, Media, Arabia</hi> the Deſart <hi>Hamburrough, Breme, Mountſerat, Piſarum, Trent, Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lizburgh, Ingolſtade,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>Norway</hi> under the <hi>Daniſh</hi> Government muſt be ſenſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble of this great Conjunction too, for it is Subject to the Sign <hi>Scorpio. Flanders,</hi> I pitty thee, and that Honourable Houſe of <hi>Auſtria,</hi> for in time you will want both Friends and Support, for the Conjunction Influence deſigns a greater blow than thou haſt had already: here are many more Kingdoms, Cities, and Corporations which muſt look to feel the dire effects of this Conjunction, as <hi>Ruſſia, Polonia, Lorrain, Campaine, Helvetia, Rhetia, Franconia, Parthia, Perſia, Ireland, Cyclades,</hi> Towns of <hi>Aſia; Bononia, Sona, Mantua, Taurentum, Panorma</hi> in <hi>Sicily, Peruvium, Caput, Hiſtriae, Brixi, Zurich, Lucerna, Nants, Herbibolis, Caraſtade, Poſuania, Leipſig, Genaſa, Novograde, Melagony, Comagena, Cappadocia, Algiers, Valentiani, Spain, Forum, Peſtorium, Taruiſum, Julium, Feſs, Gethulia, Catalonia,</hi> all theſe places are threatned with ſtrange kind of Alterations in their Government, perhaps Wars, Famine, Diſſolution, Plague, Peſtilence, Mutinies, Commotions of Armies, Plots, Treaſons, Treacheries, Maſſacres, Rebellion, and ſuch like horrid Evils; for Armies ſhall run like Lightning over a great man, Countries of <hi>Europe,</hi> and will af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>flict <hi>Chriſtendom</hi> with the Sword more than ordinary; nay, they will bring more under ſubjection within the ſpace of ten years, than any Armies have done for twice ten years laſt paſt; there will be many and unexpected Slaughters, Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>priſonments, Baniſhments, Captivities; great Slaughters and Dammages amongſt the Navies at Sea alſo, <hi>&amp;c. London,</hi> I ſhould not forget thee too, for I am affraid that thou wilt ſuffer ſome kind of Cataſtrophe e're long, from which I pray God deliver thee, for it hath been obſerved that the Planet <hi>Saturn</hi> never paſſes through the Sign <hi>Leo,</hi> but he by his Evil Influence leaves ſome conſiderable Impreſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on upon the City of <hi>London;</hi> but what this Conjunction of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter</hi> in <hi>Leo</hi> may produce, let us patiently wait to ſee the event; for Sickneſs I dread, and thoſe moſt dangerous, from which let us pray, <hi>Libera nos Domine, Good Lord deliver us,</hi> for in 1625 <hi>Saturn</hi> was in <hi>Leo,</hi> at which time a great Plague began in <hi>London,</hi> which cauſed the Parliament to remove to <hi>Oxford;</hi> and truly I do fear another great Plague in <hi>London,</hi> e're <hi>Saturn</hi> hath paſs'd the Sign <hi>Leo,</hi> 1683, and this the more, becauſe <hi>Mars</hi> was in Conjunction with <hi>Jupiter</hi> on the 8th of <hi>September,</hi> in <hi>Leo,</hi> and on the 12th day of the ſaid Month <hi>Mars</hi> was in Conjunction with <hi>Saturn,</hi> in <hi>Leo,</hi> and on the 9th of <hi>October,</hi> and 30th of <hi>January, Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter</hi> were in Conjunction in <hi>Leo,</hi> and in <hi>May,</hi> 1683, they make their laſt Conjunction in <hi>Leo,</hi> near the Degree of the Conjunction of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Mars</hi> the <hi>September</hi> before; all theſe things be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing conſidered, makes me conjecture that we ſhall have another Plague e're 84, which God divert.</p>
            <p>But in caſe we ſhould eſcape a Plague this year, and the year 84, then will Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land be the moſt happy Nation under the Sun, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The next thing I have to deliver to the World, is by what manner of means every Nation, City, and People is like to ſuffer under this Conjunction.</p>
            <p>But ſince it is impoſſible to get the true time of any Conjunction of the two Supe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riours,
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:50004:20"/>
               <hi>viz. Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter:</hi> Therefore I ſhall deliver my Judgment according to the beſt of my Reaſon.</p>
            <p>As thus, Suppoſe we place <hi>Aries</hi> upon the Aſcendant, then will this Conjucti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on fall in the Fifth Houſe, which is oppoſite to the Eleventh, and in ſquare to the Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cond and Eighth. <hi>Aries</hi> is the Aſcendant of <hi>England, France, Germany, Polonia, Bur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gundy, Denmark,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <p>Now the Second Houſe repreſents the ſubſtance of the Common People, as Houſhold-ſtuff, Moneys, Plate, Jewels, Corn, and is the proper Perſonal Eſtate of any Man: it alſo ſignifies the Countries, or Common-wealths Magazine, or Am<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munition; it likewiſe repreſents their Allies and Supports, or whatſoever is Aſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtant to them: Now, in regard this Conjunction falls in ſquare to the Second Houſe, therefore I Judge there will be a great decay in Trade, as Buying and Sel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling, and but little appearance of increaſing Eſtates, but ſudden undoing and im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poveriſhment of many a Man, as well the Yeoman, and hard labouring Farmer, as the Curious Induſtrious Mechanick; nay, I cannot perceive but that the whole Commonalty is threatned with much deceit in their Allies and Supports, whereby they may want both Ammunition and Moneys to maintain their Principles, and that in <hi>France, Germany, Polonia,</hi> &amp;c. Now ſince the Eighth Houſe is oppoſite to the Second, and doth repreſent the Inheritance of the Dead, and the Death of Mankind in general, and is the Houſe of Sadneſs, and doth alſo denote the Eſtates and Fortunes of our publick Enemies; and becauſe this Conjunction falls in ſquare to the ſame, therefore I predict according to Natural Cauſes, that many violent and ſudden Deaths will happen to the common ſort of People, and that from as violent and raging Diſeaſes; and beſides it denotes, that the Eſtates and Inheritances of ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny a Man ſhall be violently wreſted from them by thoſe which have Power and bear Rule over them, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Fifth Houſe denotes Meſſengers or Agents for Republique Embaſſadours, likewiſe Playing, Gaming, Drinking, Revelling, Joy, Pleaſures, Gifts; it alſo ſignifies Children, and Women with Child, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now in regard this Conjunction is made in the Fifth Houſe, therefore I judge much Dammage to happen to the People, through their Agents, Meſſengers, or Embaſſadours, and all ſuch things ſignified by the Fifth Houſe, as Drinking and Revelling, which may cauſe Surfeits, and the like; for <hi>Saturn</hi> Corrupts the Blood by Melancholy, and <hi>Mars</hi> by Choler; it alſo denotes many Abortions and ſtrange kind of Monſtrous Births, with much Trouble and Affliction to Children and Wo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men with Child, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now becauſe the Fifth Houſe is in Oppoſition to the Eleventh; it ſignifying the Aſſociates, Counſellors, Allies, Treaſure, Ammunition, Soldiery, and indeed all that is aſſiſtant to thoſe in Power, from which we may Conjecture that the Princes of the Earth ſhould grow very Ambitious, and ſhall waſte their Eſtates by War, and not only ſo, but be Cheated by their Allies, Counſellours, Souldiery, Servants, and Favourites, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Again, ſuppoſe we place Taurus upon the Aſcendant, then will the Conjunction happen in the Fourth Houſe, which is in oppoſition to the Tenth, and in ſquare to the Firſt and Seventh; <hi>Taurus</hi> is the Aſcendant of <hi>Ruſſia, Swedeland, Lorrain, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="5 letters">
                     <desc>•••••</desc>
                  </gap>onia, Perſia, Ireland,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <p>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> by Conſequence theſe places muſt be threatned with Plague, Peſtilence,
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:50004:21"/>
Famine and Wars, alſo much trouble and vexation in their Government; if the Tenth Houſe repreſents all thoſe in Authority, <hi>viz.</hi> Kings, Princes, Magiſtrates, Governours of Towns, Forts, Cities, Corporations, <hi>viz.</hi> Captains, Majors, Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lonels, Bayliffs, Juſtices of the Peace, all theſe ſhall find great troubles and vex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ations in their Government, Offices and Places of Truſt, it is probable ſome of them may exerciſe Tyranny upon thoſe they bear Rule over, by which means they may cauſe their Subjects to take up Arms againſt them, and that in <hi>Ruſſia, Polonia,</hi> the great, <hi>Swedeland, Parthia, Helvetia, Ireland,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <p>The Aſcendant ſignifies the ſtate of the Common People, and how it ſhall go with them, well or ill, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Seventh Houſe ſignifies Women, War, Contention, Publick Enemies, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now, becauſe both theſe Houſes are ſquared by this Conjunction, therefore I judge much publick Sorrow and Affliction to happen to the People in general belong<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to all thoſe places under <hi>Taurus,</hi> it may be both Plague and Famine, ſince this Conjunction is made in their Fourth Houſe; for <hi>Saturn,</hi> as to Natural things, por<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tends great want and ſcarcity, deſtruction of Cattle, Corn, Fruits, unwholeſome Airs, Cold, Cloudy, Foggy, Dark, Miſty Weather, Famine and Mortality, and alſo tedious Froſts, with long Winters; he alſo threatens many with long and tedious Infirmities and Diſeaſes, as <hi>Quartan</hi> Agues, Conſumption in the Reins, ill and noiſome Vapours; from whence proceeds Plagues, Hectick Feavers, and the like, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>But if we place <hi>Gemini</hi> on the Aſcendant, then will this Conjunction be in the Third Houſe, which oppoſeth the Ninth, and ſquares the Sixth and Twelfth: Then muſt all thoſe places under <hi>Gemini</hi> ſuffer much for Religions ſake, and ſhall have long and dangerous Navigations; ſmall ſucceſs in their Inland Journeys, little Love and Unity between Neighbours and Relations, alſo loſs of Cattle, both great and ſmall, ill Servants, long Impriſonments; much whiſpering amongſt a parcel of malicious Raſcals, who ſeek private Revenges, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now if we make <hi>Cancer</hi> aſcending, then ſhall this Conjunction be made in the Second Houſe, which is in ſquare to the Fifth and Eleventh, and in oppoſition to the Eighth; then muſt all thoſe places under <hi>Cancer,</hi> to wit, <hi>Scotland, Holland, Granada, Burgundy, Zeland,</hi> &amp;c. ſuffer loſs of Life and Fortune, their own Friends ſhall prove deceitful to them; yea, their neighbour Nations will prove unfaithful to them, as well as their own Embaſſadours, Meſſengers, Agents, and Truſtees, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>But if we place <hi>Leo</hi> upon the Aſcendant, then ſhall this Conjunction fall therein, the Aſcendant oppoſeth the Seventh, and looks a ſquint upon the Tenth and Fourth: <hi>Rome</hi> is under <hi>Leo,</hi> ſo is <hi>Italy, Gallia, Cicily, Aphalia, Bohemia, Turky,</hi> &amp;c. moſt of theſe places will ſuffer Devaſtation, if not a Final Cataſtrophe; their Princes ſhall be brought very low, and that through their own Pride and Ambition; they will alſo ſuffer both Fire, Plague, Peſtilence, Wars and Famine, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now ſuppoſe we place <hi>Virgo</hi> upon the Aſcendant, then will the Conjunction hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pen in the Twelfth, which is oppoſite to the Sixth, and in ſquare to the Third and Ninth. The Twelfth Houſe is the Houſe of Enmity: What ſhall any of thoſe Countries be invaded by the means of ſome private Enemies? Yea, whilſt they are a quarrelling at home about Religion, ſome other Nation will ſteal on them una<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wares; they ſhall likewiſe have many great Sea Fights, and receive great loſs and dammage thereby: <hi>Virgo</hi> deſigns the Dukedom of <hi>Athens, Meſopotamia, Babylon,
<pb n="29" facs="tcp:50004:21"/>
Achaia, Greece, Creet, Carinthia, Arthefina, Aſſyria, Gallia, Comata, Rhone, Croatia, Sileſia,</hi> &amp;c. Theſe Countries will alſo have great deſtruction amongſt their Cattle, to wit, both great and ſmall, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>But if we place <hi>Libra</hi> on the Aſcendant, then will the Conjunction be in the E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leventh Houſe; the Eleventh Houſe is in ſquare to the Second and Eighth, and op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſeth the Fifth; <hi>Libra</hi> is the Aſcendant of <hi>Auſtria, Alſatia, Livonia, Sabaudia,</hi> &amp;c. Theſe places are like to ſuffer through the unfaithfulneſs of their Friends, Servants, Favourites, Councils, Agents, Meſſengers, and Embaſſadours; alſo want of Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſion, both of Men, Moneys, and Ammunition, and all ſuch things which are neceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſary for their Supportment; they are alſo threatned with great ſlaughter of a number of Men, as well by the Sword, as by violent and raging Diſeaſes, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Thus you ſee if we place the Signs upon the Aſcendent by Succeſſion, we ſhall find by what means every Nation, Kingdom, City, and People, is like to ſuffer under the Influence of this Conjunction, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <div type="year">
               <head>Aſtrological Judgments for the Year <hi>1683.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>IN this year of 1683, we have no leſs than 3 Eclipſes of the Sun and Moon in <hi>Leo</hi> and <hi>Aquarius,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <p>January the <hi>17.</hi> O Eclipſed viſible in ♒.</p>
                     <p>January the <hi>30.</hi> ♄ ♃ ☌ ♌.</p>
                     <p>February <hi>1.</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> Eclipſed inviſible in ♌.</p>
                     <p>May <hi>2.</hi> ♄ ♃ ☌ ♌.</p>
                     <p>July <hi>28.</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> Eclipſed inviſible in ♒.</p>
                  </note> beſides 2 Conjunctions of the Superiours, <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter,</hi> who meet with many Oppoſitions of the leſſer Planets, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the time of their ſecond Conjunction on <hi>January</hi> the 30th, which doth declare the unſettled Condition of the Vulgar and Common People, and that they dread ſome great Troubles or Calamity too near approaching; but whethether it be Plague, Peſtilence, Wars, or Famine, I ſhall give ſwift winged Time leave to diſcover the truth thereof: In the beginning of <hi>May Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter</hi> make their laſt Conjunction in that Regal Sign <hi>Leo,</hi> but ſome few days before they meet with a ſquare of the Sun from <hi>Taurus,</hi> therefore whatever Great Perſon of <hi>Europe</hi> hath <hi>Leo</hi> aſcending at his Birth, ſhall ſuffer Troubles with loſs of Honour; nay, Kings and Princes ſhall alſo find many troubles and vex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ations in their Government, and Governours of Towns, Forts and Cities ſhall re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive much Loſs and Dammage, and in all probability many of them may be called to an account by their Superiours, and thoſe in particular which abode in thoſe places under <hi>Taurus, Scorpio, Leo,</hi> and <hi>Aquarius,</hi> as <hi>Rome, Alſatia, Spain, Hungary, Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtria, Dalmatia, Macedonia, Greece, Gaunt, Flanders, Brandenburgh, Muſcovia, Albania,</hi> theſe places are alſo threatned with Fires, Wars, Famine, Plague, Peſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lence, Rebellion, or ſuch like Calamities, <hi>&amp;c. Oxford, Holland, Hungary,</hi> and the <hi>Turk</hi> himſelf is much herein concerned; and beſides, <hi>Italy</hi> mones, and <hi>Spain</hi> doth cry, and <hi>London</hi> fears the Peſtilence, from which, I pray <hi>Good Lord deliver us</hi> this
<pb n="30" facs="tcp:50004:22"/>
year, and for ever more, <hi>faxit Deus, Amen,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>Mars</hi> his long Trancite through the Sign <hi>Libra,</hi> doth now threaten the Noble <hi>Auſtrian</hi> Family with many Afflictions, for the Princes of <hi>Germany</hi> will be unfaithful to him, which may cauſe the Death of many of the Inhabitants: thoſe places which are under <hi>Aries</hi> will be great Sufferers too, as <hi>Burgundy, Denmark, France, Germany, Polonia, England;</hi> if I am not miſtaken in my Judgment, we ſhall hear of ſome Deſtruction amongſt the Natives in <hi>France,</hi> and that ſome kind of Maſſacre, if not timely prevented; But <hi>bleſſed are thoſe which dye in the Lord, for they reſt from their Labour.</hi> Oh the Condi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of the common People! they ſhall ſuffer many Troubles and Calamities in that Country, yea, in the very middle thereof, but before they will indure it long they will join together and cauſe a Rebellion, then wo to thoſe which blowed the Fire of Deſtruction, for they are taken in the Flame themſelves, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="year">
               <head>Aſtrological Judgments for the Year <hi>1684.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <p>January the 6th. ☉ Eclipſ. inviſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble in ♑.</p>
                     <p>January the <hi>3.</hi> ☍ ♄ ♂ from ♍ and ♓.</p>
                     <p>June <hi>17.</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> Eclipſed viſible in ♑.</p>
                     <p>July the <hi>2.</hi> ☉ Eclipſ. viſible in ♋.</p>
                     <p>October <hi>3.</hi> ♂ ☌ ♍ <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> Ecclipſed,</p>
                     <p>Decemb. <hi>11.</hi> in ♋. viſible.</p>
                  </note>HEre is an Oppoſition of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Mars</hi> on <hi>January</hi> the 3d, from <hi>Virgo</hi> and <hi>Piſces;</hi> and there is alſo a notable Conjunction of thoſe two Malefacts on the 3d of <hi>October,</hi> in 13 Degrees of <hi>Virgo,</hi> and is in ſquare to the Conjunctions of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter,</hi> 1603, and 1663, therefore whatever Prince of <hi>Europe</hi> hath about 13 Degrees of <hi>Virgo</hi> aſcending at his Birth muſt yield to pale Death this year, for he will not be denied by the Princes of the Earth, when their time is come. The King of <hi>France</hi> will go near to have his Honour Eclipſed this year, for this Conjunction happens in the Mid-Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven of his Nativity; this Conjunction likewiſe threatens <hi>Babylon, Aſſyria, Gallia, Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rinthia,</hi> the Dukedome of <hi>Athens, Meſopotamia, Hiruſalem, Achaia, Greece, Creet, Lyons, Paris</hi> and <hi>Baſil</hi> with Mutinies, Tumults, Wars, Commotions of Armies, Treacheries, and ſtrange Rebellion: <hi>Spain</hi> I pity thy condition, for thou art like to have great loſſes, both by Sea and Land; and beſides in many more Countries there will be great ſlaughter of Men where there is frequent motions of Armies, eſpecial<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly in <hi>France;</hi> for I fear ſome kind of Bloody Maſſacre there, amongſt the poor Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tives, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> There is no leſs than four Eclipſes this year, and three of them viſible; they fall in <hi>Cancer</hi> and <hi>Capricorn.</hi> Now the Ancients tell us that Eclipſes in <hi>Capricorn,</hi> are the Fore-runners of the ſterility of the Earth, and the Tumultuary motions of Princes, and that in thoſe places under the Sign <hi>Capricorn;</hi> it likewiſe ſignifies, that ſome Great and Eminent Perſon ſhall depart this Life in a terrible and deplorable Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dition, and that Men ſhall be given to ſlander and betray one another; and thoſe E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clipſes in <hi>Cancer</hi> excite mens minds to quarrel and new attempts of War, with Trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chery and Sedition; alſo thundring noiſes and uproars in and about Religion, they alſo threaten the Small Pox, Conſumption, Dropſies, with violent pains in the Stomach, and that to thoſe perſons and places ſubject to the Signs <hi>Cancer</hi> and <hi>Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pricorn,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="year">
               <pb n="31" facs="tcp:50004:22"/>
               <head>Aſtrological Judgments for the Year <hi>1685.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>NOw the late Conjuction of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Mars</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gins to opperate to purpoſe;<note place="margin">
                     <p>June the <hi>6.</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> Eclipſed inviſible in ♐.</p>
                     <p>June the <hi>21,</hi> ☉ Eclipſed viſible in ♋.</p>
                     <p>November the <hi>30,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> Eclipſ. viſible and total in ♊ Londons Sign.</p>
                  </note> therefore the King of <hi>France,</hi> if he be alive, may expect to be driven from his own Confines or abode, and that by his own Subjects, if not, it is probable he may come to ſome ſudden and unexpected Deſtruction, either by Poiſon, or by ſome other means equivolent, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Here is no leſs than 3 Eclipſes this year, between thoſe glorious Lamps of Heaven, that is one of the Sun, and two of the Moon: The firſt is a Lunar Eclipſe, and falls in <hi>Sagitarius;</hi> therefore <hi>Hungary, Morovia, Dalmatia, Sclavonia</hi> and <hi>Spain</hi> ſeek out for a good Phyſitian, for you are threatned with a Plague, or ſome other violent Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtempers equivolent; the two laſt Eclipſes are made in <hi>Gemini</hi> and <hi>Cancer;</hi> the Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cond which is of the Sun in <hi>Cancer,</hi> is of no great ſignification, ſince it is inviſible and very ſmall; yet Men will be apt to Cheat and Cozen one another, and that under the pretence and ſpecies of Religion; beſides this Eclipſe may cauſe various Winds and alterations of Weather, whereby the Air will be much troubled, and that in <hi>Burgundy, Holland, Scotland, Granado, Africa, Conſtantinople, Tunis, Venice,</hi> and <hi>Genoa;</hi> but the Third and laſt Eclipſe of the Moon in <hi>Gemini</hi> is of more eminent ſig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nification to thoſe places under the ſign of the Eclipſe, and I fear they will feel its dire effects; the Eclipſe it ſelf is made in the Mid-Heaven, and <hi>Virgo</hi> aſcends, as may be ſeen by this following Figure, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
               <figure>
                  <head>
                     <hi>November the</hi> 30th, 1685, 11 <hi>hours P. M.</hi> 
                     <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> 
                     <hi>Eclipſed viſible and total, Lat.</hi> 51 <hi>degr.</hi> 3½, <hi>Londini.</hi>
                  </head>
               </figure>
               <p>
                  <pb n="32" facs="tcp:50004:23"/>
                  <hi>Mercury</hi> rules both the Houſes, and he is in his detriment with <hi>Cauda,</hi> and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>buſt of the Sun; now if the Tenth Houſe doth repreſent all thoſe in Authority, whether they be Kings, Princes, or Magiſtrates, then they muſt expect to find ſome ſudden noiſes or motions of Arms within the bounds of their Government, and particular in thoſe places under the Signs <hi>Gemini</hi> and <hi>Virgo</hi> where Armies are, yet there will be a quick diſpatch made of thoſe differences, and the Land of <hi>Vir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>go</hi> will go near to have it; <hi>Saturn</hi> beholds <hi>Mercury,</hi> the Sun, and place of the Eclipſe by an envious Quadrat, and <hi>Mercury</hi> himſelf, who is Lord of the Eclipſe, beholds the defect by an Oppoſition, which ſeems unto me, as if all places under the Signs <hi>Virgo</hi> and <hi>Piſces, Gemini</hi> and <hi>Sagitarius</hi> were in Election to be up in Arms againſt a great and potent Enemy. Now thoſe places under the Signs nominated are <hi>Portu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gal, Normandy</hi> in <hi>France, Hungary, Spain, Dalmatia, Moravia, Coratia, Babylon, Scla<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>onia, Sardinia, Sweedland, Brabant, Lumbardy, England, Wertenburgh</hi> that Dukedom, <hi>Hircania, Armenia, Celtica,</hi> and the Dukedome of <hi>Athens, &amp;c. Swede<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land</hi> about this time is inclinable to peace, and I think it the beſt of their play, for if they ſlip ſuch an opportunity, as they are likely to have, they will repent it when 'tis too late: The <hi>Auſtrian</hi> Family ſuffers detriment through and by the means of the <hi>Hungarians.</hi> The <hi>Muſcovites</hi> ſeem to be in a good proſperous Condition, but the <hi>Tartar</hi> threatens <hi>Europe</hi> either with Fire or Sword, or both: <hi>They aim, but they miſs their mark,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="year">
               <head>Aſtrological Judgments for the Year <hi>1686.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <p>January the <hi>20.</hi> ☍ ♄ ♂ from ♍ and ♓.</p>
                     <p>October <hi>23,</hi> ☌ ♄ ♂ in ♎.</p>
                     <p>November the <hi>19,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> Eclipſed viſible in ♊.</p>
                     <p>December the <hi>23.</hi> ⚹ ♄ ♃ in ♎ and ♐.</p>
                  </note>THis year begins with an Oppoſition of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Mars,</hi> from <hi>Virgo</hi> and <hi>Piſces;</hi> and about <hi>October</hi> the 23d, thoſe two Malefacts meet in Conjunction in <hi>Libra:</hi> Now let thoſe Jeſuitical Tribe of Prieſts, and Conclave of Cardinals look to it, for they ſhall dearly pay for their Treacherous Villanous actions; for their Monaſteries ſhall be diſſolved, and they themſelves de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtroyed, or elſe taken Captives: The Noble <hi>Auſtrian</hi> Family is alſo in much danger of falling into the Hands of a ſtrong and potent Enemy, therefore is threatned with Devaſtation; neither doth it go well with <hi>Holland, Scotlaad, Livonia, Delphinate, Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſatia, Baſtrina, Oeſim, Thuſia, Seres, Thebaida, Lisbone, Cajetam, Laudam, Spiers,</hi> and <hi>Frankford,</hi> for <hi>Holland</hi> is threatned with many loſſes, and <hi>Scotland</hi> will not be much be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hind hand, but <hi>Auſtria, Alſatia, Livonia,</hi> and ſeveral more places in <hi>Germany</hi> are threat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned with Fire and Sword, and ſuch like Calamities: The <hi>French</hi> are alſo a little fearful, and that not without juſt cauſe; for they cannot promiſe themſelves Security, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> In this year we have only one Eclipſe, and that of the Moon, it falls in the firſt Face of <hi>Gemini,</hi> on the 19th day of <hi>November,</hi> at eleven of the Clock at Night, to which time I have Erected this following Scheme.</p>
               <figure>
                  <head>
                     <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> 
                     <hi>Eclipſed November the</hi> 19th, 1686, <hi>at</hi> 11 <hi>hours P. M. die</hi> ♀ <hi>Lat.</hi> 51 <hi>degr.</hi> 3½, <hi>Londini.</hi>
                  </head>
               </figure>
               <p>This Eclipſe begins in the Tenth Houſe, and ends in the Ninth Angle; the Sun's beſieged between the Bodies of <hi>Jupiter</hi> and <hi>Mercury,</hi> and all three oppoſe the Eclip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed Moon, and that from as violent fixed Stars as ſhe her ſelf is near, for ſhe is with <hi>oculus Tauri,</hi> and they with <hi>Cor Scorpi</hi> and <hi>Caput Herculis; Mercury</hi> is Lord of the Aſcendant, and in part Ruler of the Mid-heaven: <hi>Jupiter</hi> is Lord of the 7th, and in part Ruler of the Fourth, ſtrong in his own Houſe, and in <hi>Quartile</hi> to the Degree aſcending: <hi>London</hi> thou art much concerned in this Eclipſe, let thy Magiſtrates therefore look to it, and ſee that they do nothing of Injuſtice, for if they do they muſt expect to pay for their folly; for the the Common People will expect to have Juſtice done them; therefore thoſe which act to the contrary, may Repent when it is too late, <hi>&amp;c. Mercury,</hi> Lord of thy Aſcendant being Combuſt, and in his Detriment, ſhews that thou ſhould have but bad Trading this year, but if thou doſt but conſider the Condition of many more Countries and Places in <hi>Europe,</hi> thou wouldſt think thy ſelf happy, ſince thy Foundation ſtands firm and unſhaken, when others are invaded, and that by a cloak and ſhew of Friendſhip, <hi>&amp;c. London</hi> thou muſt expect to have many Embaſſadours this year 1686, to the Governour of thy Kingdom, for <hi>Saturn</hi> Lord of the Fifth in this Figure, is in <hi>Sextile</hi> to <hi>Mercury,</hi> Lord of the Aſcendant and place Eclipſed, and is likewiſe in <hi>Sextile</hi> to <hi>Jupiter</hi> and the <hi>Sun,</hi> and in <hi>Trine</hi> to the Eclipſed <hi>Moon</hi> in thy Aſcendent: This Eclipſe alſo denotes In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>curſions of Armies into thoſe Countries and Places under <hi>Gemini, Virgo, Sagitarius,</hi> and <hi>Piſces,</hi> as <hi>Flanders, Brabant, Sardinia, Lumbardy, Marmarica, Martiania, Spain, Dalmatia, Sclavonia, Hungary, Moravia, Miſnia, Achaia, Greece, Creet, Croatia, Carinthia, Meſopotamia, Babylon, Normandy, Galatia, Portugal, Cicilia,</hi> and many more places which you may read of in Mr. <hi>Coley</hi>'s <hi>Clavis of Aſtrology,</hi> page 91, 92, 93, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Many of theſe places is alſo threatned with Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mine and great Mortalities, as will plainly appear before the Sun hath gone another
<pb n="34" facs="tcp:50004:24"/>
Revolution; and to conclude, about the 23d day of <hi>December,</hi> there happens a <hi>Sextile</hi> between <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter,</hi> from <hi>Libra</hi> and <hi>Sagitarius,</hi> both in their own eſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſential Dignities, which ſhews a ſtrong inclination amongſt the Princes of <hi>Europe,</hi> for a Confirmation of Peace and Unity in many Places and Countries; but by reaſon <hi>Saturn</hi> has lately paſſed the place of his Conjunction with <hi>Mars,</hi> therefore I fear it will be hardly accompliſhed as yet in all places, although it will in ſome: The Sun never ſhines always in one place, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="year">
               <head>Aſtrological Judgments for the Year <hi>1687.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <p>February the <hi>16</hi> ☌ ♃ ♂ in ♐.</p>
                     <p>May the <hi>1,</hi> ☉ Eclipſed viſible in England, it happens in ♉ a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongſt the Pleiades.</p>
                     <p>October the <hi>26,</hi> ☉ Eclipſed in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſible in ♏.</p>
                  </note>ON the 16 day of <hi>February</hi> here is a Conjunction with <hi>Mars</hi> and <hi>Jupiter</hi> in <hi>Sagitarius,</hi> and in the Figure of the <hi>Sun</hi>'s Revolution, <hi>March</hi> the 9th, about 20 Hours <hi>poſt</hi> Meridian, <hi>Mars</hi> and <hi>Saturn</hi> applies to a ſquare of each other, and that from their own Exal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tations; and beſides <hi>Saturn</hi> receives no leſs than three Oppoſitions, and thoſe by <hi>Venus, Mercury,</hi> and the <hi>Sun,</hi> and <hi>Mars</hi> two <hi>Quartils</hi> by <hi>Mercury</hi> and the <hi>Sun,</hi> and all from <hi>Aries;</hi> ſuch Poſitions as theſe do afflict all thoſe places ſubject to the Signs <hi>Aries, Libra,</hi> and <hi>Capricorn,</hi> with Wars and Commoti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons of Armies: The Subjects in many places will be apt to Rebel againſt their Supe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riours, and that in <hi>France,</hi> if I miſtake not; which if they do, the <hi>Romiſh</hi> Party will come off by the lee, for their Univerſal deſtruction is drawing on, and then they will repent their being ſo cruel and barbarous to thoſe innocent and harmleſs Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teſtants: <hi>Saturn</hi> in <hi>Libra,</hi> ſquared by <hi>Mars,</hi> ſhews the Sword ſtill to be in action in ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny places under the Sign <hi>Libra,</hi> as <hi>Caſpia, Alſatia, Baſtrina, Thebaida, Livonia, Sabandia, Austria, Antwerp, Delphinat, Oeſim, Trogloditica, Lisbone, Friburgh, Franckford,</hi> and thoſe under <hi>Capricorn</hi> muſt look to feel a little too, e're <hi>Mars</hi> paſs through that Sign, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>In this year we have but two Eclipſes, and thoſe both of the <hi>Sun,</hi> the one in <hi>Tau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rus,</hi> and the other in <hi>Scorpio:</hi> The Firſt falls on <hi>May</hi> the firſt, about a quarter of an hour after Noon, to which time I have erected this following Scheme.</p>
               <figure>
                  <head>☉ <hi>Eclipſed May the</hi> 1ſt, 1687, 1⅕, <hi>P. M. Latitud.</hi> 51 <hi>degr.</hi> 3½, <hi>Londini, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </head>
               </figure>
               <p>Now in regard the Eclipſed Sun is Lord of the Twelfth, therefore I judge it to be the fore-runner both of Plague, Peſtilence and Famine, mortalitly in and amongſt Oxen, Bulls, Cows, and Horſes, and that in <hi>Ruſſia, Polonia, Swedeland, Lorrain, Campania, Helvetia, Rhetia, Franconia, Parthia, Perſia, Ireland, Cyclades,</hi> the Iſlands <hi>Cyprus,</hi> the Sea Towns of <hi>Aſia</hi> the leſs, <hi>Bononia, Sona, Mantua, Tarentum, &amp;c.</hi> for <hi>Taurus</hi> is an Earthy Sign, and repreſents all ſuch kind of Cattle: The Second Eclipſe is of the Sun alſo, and falls in that Treacherous Sign <hi>Scorpio,</hi> which ſhews ſome ſudden miſchief will fall upon ſome King, whoſe mind is averſe to War; and if the King of <hi>France</hi> be now living, tell him, I give him warning to pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vide for a change, for the thread of his Life hath ſpun out its full length: For this laſt Eclipſe of the Sun in <hi>Scorpio,</hi> who was giver of life at his Birth, falls upon the very Degree of his Horroſcope, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> I judg alſo that this Eclipſe will cauſe War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>like Tumults, Murthers, Treaſons, Treacheries, Plots, Diſſentions, Captivities, and all under-hand practices, and my Reaſon is this, becauſe it is made in the aſcending part of Heaven, and that particular to thoſe Perſons under <hi>Taurus, Scorpio, Leo</hi> and <hi>Aquarius.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="year">
               <pb n="36" facs="tcp:50004:25"/>
               <head>Aſtrological Judgments for the Year <hi>1688.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <p>January the <hi>23,</hi> ☍ ♄ ♂ from ♈ and ♎</p>
                     <p>March the <hi>11,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:quadrine">□</g> ♄ ♃ from ♎ and ♑.</p>
                     <p>April the <hi>5,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> Eclipſed invi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſible in ♎.</p>
                     <p>April the <hi>20,</hi> ☉ Eclipſed in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſible in ♉.</p>
                     <p>July <hi>22,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:quadrine">□</g> ♄ ♃ ♎ ♑.</p>
                     <p>
                        <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> Eclipſed in ♈ inviſible, Sep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tember the <hi>29.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>October <hi>14,</hi> ☉ Eclipſed viſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble in ♏ November the <hi>7,</hi> ☌ ♄ ♂ in ♏.</p>
                  </note>THis year begins with an Oppoſition of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Mars,</hi> from <hi>Aries</hi> and <hi>Libra;</hi> and on the 11th day of <hi>March</hi> following <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter</hi> make their firſt ſquare Aſpect from <hi>Libra</hi> and <hi>Capricorn,</hi> and the ſecond Quadrat of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter</hi> falls from <hi>Libra</hi> and <hi>Capricorn:</hi> There is likewiſe a notable Conjuncti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Mars,</hi> on the 7th day of <hi>December,</hi> in that treacherous Sign <hi>Scorpio;</hi> and we have no leſs than four Eclipſes of the Luminaries this year, <hi>viz.</hi> Two of the Sun, and two of the Moon, but none vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſible, only the laſt defect of the Sun in <hi>Scorpio,</hi> and that falls in the very ſame Degree of the Conjunction of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Mars,</hi> which happens on the 7th day of <hi>November</hi> following; from all theſe Configurations we may rationally judg, that <hi>Italy,</hi> with that noble Houſe of <hi>Auſtria,</hi> are great ſufferers; for <hi>Italy</hi> mourns to think of the troubles ſhe hath and is to undergo: The noble <hi>Auſtrians</hi> are much af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>flicted by the Poſition of <hi>Saturn</hi> in <hi>Libra:</hi> Oh ſhall that Prince be always troubled and perplexed by the Jeſuitical Tribe, who would lead him to his own Deſtruction, juſt as a Sheep is led to the Slaughter? No, no, here is an Eclipſe of the Sun in <hi>Scorpio,</hi> and preſently after a Conjunction between the two Malefacts, <hi>viz. Saturn</hi> and <hi>Mars</hi> in the very Degree thereof, therefore look to it <hi>TOM Jeſuit,</hi> for as thou haſt dug a Pit for another, thou muſt even look to fall into it thy ſelf, for <hi>Mars</hi> is Lord of the Aſcendant, and the Eclipſe it ſelf is made therein; therefore we can expect nothing but Wars and Tumults, Treacheries, Mutanies, Maſſacres, Rebellion, and that I fear in <hi>Ireland.</hi> The <hi>Turk</hi> will alſo be much afflicted with fo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reign loſſes; nay, not only ſo, but he ſhall ſuffer many broyls at home, and the Pope himſelf muſt look about him, for <hi>Mars</hi> is clearly for nothing but down-right blows, whereby he knocks all former Treaties on the Head, cauſing Hatred, Plots, Cap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tivities, Slaughters, Treacheries, whereby nothing but confuſion follows, and that in <hi>Norway, Bavaria, Metagony, Cappadocia, Feſs, Catalonia, Togata, Gallia, Bohe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mia, Italy, Turky, Swedeland, Polonia, Ruſſia, Ireland, Rome,</hi> and all places under <hi>Taurus, Scorpio, Leo,</hi> and <hi>Aquarius,</hi> muſt look to ſuffer and feel the dire effects of this Eclipſe, beſides there are many places that are like to ſuffer by the former, for an Eclipſe of the Moon in the laſt Face of <hi>Libra,</hi> is the fore-runner of the Death of ſome Noble and Illuſtrious Men under the Sign of the Eclipſe, alſo thoſe Eclipſes of the Sun and Moon in the ſecond Faces of <hi>Taurus</hi> and <hi>Aries,</hi> do prenote, innumera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble Difficulties, and many Diſcommodities to Travellers, and to ſuch as bear Children many Abortions, and Births not natural, or Monſters are produced, likewiſe Peſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lence, and Fatality in moſt Diſeaſes, few fall ſick that eſcape, and that in thoſe places under the Signs wherein the Eclipſes happen, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="year">
               <pb n="37" facs="tcp:50004:25"/>
               <head>Aſtrological Judgments for the Year <hi>1689.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>ON the 4th day of <hi>January Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter</hi> make their laſt ſquare from <hi>Scorpio</hi> and <hi>Aquarius,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <p>January <hi>4,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:quadrine">□</g> ♄ ♃, ♏ ♒.</p>
                     <p>March <hi>25,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> Eclipſed viſible in ♎</p>
                     <p>July <hi>7,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:trine">△</g> ♄ ♃ ♎ ♒.</p>
                     <p>September <hi>1<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> Eclipſed in ♈, inviſible.</p>
                     <p>September <hi>22,</hi> ☍ ♄ ♂, ♉ ♏.</p>
                  </note> and here is likewiſe an Oppoſition between <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Mars,</hi> from <hi>Taurus</hi> and <hi>Scorpio:</hi> On the 22d day of <hi>September</hi> we have likewiſe a <hi>Trine</hi> of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter;</hi> on <hi>Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly,</hi> the 7th, from <hi>Libra</hi> and <hi>Aquarius,</hi> we have alſo two Eclipſes of the Moon, the one in <hi>Aries,</hi> and the other in <hi>Libra,</hi> therefore were it not for the ſquare of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter,</hi> and the oppo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſition of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Mars,</hi> we might expect to ſee a mitigation of ſorrow, nay, probable an end of our troubles in this World; for the Eclipſe of the Moon, in the ſecond Face of <hi>Libra</hi> denotes a rot amongſt petty Foggers, Informers, Catchpoles, Trepanners, and ſuch like Cattle, for they ſhall all ſuffer for their former Rogue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry, for the Sun in <hi>Aries</hi> promiſeth many particular bleſſings to the Land of <hi>England,</hi> but the oppoſition of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Mars</hi> from <hi>Taurus</hi> and <hi>Scorpio</hi> threatens great Affli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctions to <hi>Ireland, Swedeland,</hi> and <hi>Norway Ruſſia,</hi> and <hi>Polonia;</hi> and all thoſe Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tries under <hi>Taurus</hi> and <hi>Scorpio</hi> are much herein concerned, for <hi>Hamburgh</hi> and <hi>Den<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mark</hi> are fearful, Wars in <hi>Swedeland</hi> and <hi>Norway,</hi> uproars in <hi>Ireland,</hi> and the <hi>Algiers</hi> Ships taken and deſtroyed, and their men made Captives: Now <hi>Austria, Alſatia, Livo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nia,</hi> and <hi>Sabaudia,</hi> begin to repent their former loſſes, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="year">
               <head>Aſtrological Judgments for the Year <hi>1690.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>IN this preſent year 1690,<note place="margin">
                     <p>February the <hi>28,</hi> ☉ Eclipſed in ♓, inviſible.</p>
                     <p>March the <hi>8,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:trine">△</g> ♄ ♃ from ♏ and ♓.</p>
                     <p>March the <hi>14,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> Eclipſed in ♎, inviſible.</p>
                     <p>Auguſt the <hi>24,</hi> ☉ Eclipſed in ♍ inviſible.</p>
                     <p>September <hi>8,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> Eclipſed in ♓, viſible.</p>
                     <p>November the <hi>20,</hi> ☌ ♄ ♂ in Scorpio.</p>
                  </note> we have no leſs than four Eclipſes of the Luminaries, beſides a <hi>Trine</hi> of <hi>Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter,</hi> in <hi>Scorpio</hi> and <hi>Piſces,</hi> and alſo a nota<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble Conjunction of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Mars</hi> in <hi>Scorpio,</hi> from which Configurations we may rationally predict an uni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſal change, for all <hi>Europe</hi> is up in Arms: Oh <hi>Ita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly,</hi> what dangers and troubles art thou like to undergo! for thou canſt expect nothing but miſchief to fall upon thee, for thoſe unſpeakable Villanies thou haſt been Guilty of: Oh the ſtrange miſchiefs, Plots and Trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cheries there are in the minds of Men! This Conjuncti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on falls in ſquare to the Conjunction of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter,</hi> 1682: Now <hi>Italy</hi> and <hi>Rome,</hi> where are all thy Princes with their Jeſuitical Tribe? what unlooked and unhoped for Deaths are ſome of them like to endure! for <hi>Mars</hi> threatens them with Wars,
<pb n="38" facs="tcp:50004:26"/>
Commotions, Inſurrections, Maſſacres, Perſecutions, and Murthers, But <hi>England</hi> be thou content, for thy Condition is better than any, ſince thou injoyeſt both Peace, and Tranquility, God continue it; but <hi>Ireland</hi> is full of Troubles and Vexations, and beſides here is a longer time of Sufferings appointed for that place, and indeed many more are threatned with Wars, Sedition, Cruelty, Furiouſneſs, and Inhuma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nity of Soldiers, and that from the Eclipſe of the Sun, in the laſt Face of <hi>Piſces,</hi> which influenceth over <hi>Garamentes, Portugal, Calabriana, Galatia, Cilicia, Lydia, Normandy,</hi> &amp;c. The Eclipſe of the Moon in <hi>Libra,</hi> provoketh furious and tempe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtuous ſtorms of Hail to happen in ſeveral places under the Sign <hi>Libra;</hi> and the E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clipſe of the Sun in the ſecond Face of <hi>Virgo</hi> doth threaten thoſe places under the ſaid Conſtellation with Famine, Peſtilence, Seditions, and great Droughts, hinder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the plentiful Crops of Summer Corn; here are alſo threatned many Robberies by Land, and Pyracies and Troubles by Sea, and that from the Eclipſe of the Moon in the laſt Face of <hi>Piſces;</hi> now what places <hi>Virgo</hi> and <hi>Piſces</hi> doth repreſent, you may find in Mr. <hi>Coley</hi>'s <hi>Clavis of Aſtrology,</hi> as I have declared ſeveral times already, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="year">
               <head>Aſtrological Judgments for the Year <hi>1691.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <p>February <hi>18,</hi> ☉ Eclipſed invi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſible in ♓.</p>
                     <p>July the <hi>25,</hi> ☍ ♄ ♂ from ♉ and ♏.</p>
                     <p>Auguſt the <hi>13,</hi> ☉ Eclipſed viſible in ♍.</p>
                  </note>WE have only two Eclipſes this year, and they both of the Sun, the one being in <hi>Piſces,</hi> and the other in <hi>Virgo;</hi> we have alſo a very remarkable Op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſition between the two Malefacts, <hi>viz. Saturn</hi> and <hi>Mars,</hi> from <hi>Taurus</hi> and <hi>Scorpio,</hi> and it happens in the very degree of their laſt Conjunction: Therefore from theſe Configurations, I judge that this will be a year of great action, and that in <hi>Ruſſia, Swedeland, Polonia, Lorraine, Parthia, Campania, Franconia, Norway, Bavaria, Cappadocia, Catalonia: Ireland</hi> ſtill continues in Troubles, and ſuffers great loſſes: <hi>Swedeland</hi> now begins to repent their medling with War, but <hi>Ruſſia,</hi> and they too, are both involved into that trouble, which they themſelves know not which way to get out: Oh what perplexity is there! for <hi>Mars</hi> in this Oppoſition being amongſt the Pleiades, and <hi>Saturn</hi> in Oppoſition to that turbulent Conſtellation, whoſe effects will not only be ſeen in the Air, but alſo in the Actions and Paſſions of Humane kind; therefore all thoſe Countries under the Signs <hi>Taurus</hi> and <hi>Scorpio</hi> muſt look to feel ſome ſevere Correction, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Likewiſe the Eclipſe of the Sun, in the firſt Face of <hi>Piſces,</hi> will have ſome ſecret influence over <hi>Cilicia, Calabri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ana, Portugal, Galatia, Normandy, Phaſunia, Naſamonia</hi> in <hi>Libia, Garamentes</hi> in <hi>Ly<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dia,</hi> &amp;c. But the Eclipſe of the Sun in the Face of <hi>Virgo,</hi> will ſhew its dire Effects in <hi>Achaia, Greece, Creet, Carinthia, Meſopotamia, Babylon, Aſſyria, Baſil, Lyons,</hi> and <hi>Paris</hi> in particular, becauſe of their wicked Deſigns againſt the poor Proteſtant Party: Oh what Conſultations have they againſt thoſe innocent Souls, how they may cut them off either by Maſſacre, or ſome other means, but I hope they will make good the old Proverb: <hi>He that builds a Gallows for another, may chance to be hanged thereon himſelf,</hi> &amp;c. This Eclipſe of the Sun in the firſt Face of <hi>Virgo</hi> argues the grievous Calamity and death of ſome certain King, in the Confines of <hi>Virgo,</hi> and the firſt Eclipſe of the Sun in <hi>Piſces,</hi> bringeth ſadneſs and anxiety to thoſe we call Prieſts,
<pb n="39" facs="tcp:50004:26"/>
and Religious Houſes, and all this to happen to thoſe places under <hi>Virgo</hi> and <hi>Piſces, &amp;c.</hi> The <hi>Trine</hi> of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter</hi> in <hi>Scorpion</hi> and <hi>Piſces</hi> laſt year, did cauſe a great many worthy Perſons to endeavour a Reconciliation of thoſe differences amongſt ſome Nations; and in all probability there might be Leagues and Articles made be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween ſome Princes of <hi>Europe,</hi> but if there were, I judge it was to wage War againſt ſome other Nation or Nations, for the next year, 1692, <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter</hi> make two Oppoſitions from <hi>Gemini</hi> and <hi>Sagitarius, &amp;c. England</hi> be thou content, for thou reſts upon a Rock, and thy Foundation ſtands unſhaken, and this ſhall ſuffice for the year 1691, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="year">
               <head>Aſtrological Judgments for the Year <hi>1692.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>IN this year we have no leſs than two Oppoſitions be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <p>February the <hi>6,</hi> ☉ Eclipſed in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſible in ♒.</p>
                     <p>June the <hi>12,</hi> ☍ ♄ ♃ from ♊ and ♐.</p>
                     <p>Auguſt the <hi>2,</hi> ☉ Eclipſed viſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble in <hi>20</hi> degr. ♌.</p>
                     <p>November the <hi>29,</hi> ☌ ♄ ♂ in ♐.</p>
                     <p>December the <hi>3,</hi> ☍ ♄ ♃ from ♊ and ♐.</p>
                     <p>December the <hi>27,</hi> ☉ Eclipſed viſible in ♌.</p>
                     <p>January the <hi>23,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> Eclipſed inviſible in ♌.</p>
                     <p>July the <hi>17,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> Eclipſed, vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſible in ♒.</p>
                  </note> from <hi>Gemini</hi> and <hi>Sagita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rius:</hi> There is likewiſe a famous Conjunction of <hi>Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turn</hi> and <hi>Mars;</hi> and no leſs than five Eclipſes of the Luminaries, <hi>viz.</hi> Three of the Sun, and two of the Moon: The ſecond Eclipſe of the Sun, which hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pens on the ſecond day of <hi>August,</hi> falls in the very Degree of the firſt Conjunction of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter,</hi> 1682, in <hi>October;</hi> likewiſe the firſt Eclipſe of the Moon, falls in the very Degree of the Third Conjunction of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter</hi> in <hi>May</hi> 1683; now <hi>Italy</hi> and <hi>Spain,</hi> how are you afflicted? If you have ſcarcity of Grain, and your People dye for want of Bread, pray think of me, for now the triple Conjunction of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>piter</hi> in 1682 and 83, begins to opperate to purpoſe; therefore if there be ever a Pope now, he muſt dye, he cannot avoid it, but in what Nature time will beſt diſco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver; and beſides the People in thoſe Countries will be apt to Rebel againſt their Governours, for the Eclipſe of the Sun in <hi>Leo,</hi> declares dammage to Kings; nay, both Death and Baniſhment; it may be you want a Reaſon, concerning the Peoples Rebelling againſt their Superiours; well, you ſhall not want for a ſatisfaction; <hi>Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turn</hi> and <hi>Mars</hi> are in Conjunction nearer the place of the new Star which appeared in 1604, and they are both in Oppoſition to <hi>Jupiter,</hi> ſuch prodigious Conjunctions and Aſpects as theſe, produce none but Rebels, and ſuch kind of Treacherous Vil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lains, <hi>&amp;c. Moravia, Miſnia, Sardinia, Lumbardy, Flanders, Brabant, Armenia, Martiania, Dalmatia, Hungary, Moravia, Sclavonia, Gallia, Togata, Sicily, Aphalia, Bohemia, Pheneſia, Emilia, Chaldea, Rome, Damaſco, Prague, Confluant, Sarmatia, Tartary,</hi> the great <hi>Moſel, Piemont, Media, Swedeland, Turkey,</hi> all theſe places are much concerned this year; <hi>England</hi> and <hi>France</hi> are much concerned herein alſo, but <hi>France</hi> is more concerned than <hi>England,</hi> for they are full of tribulation, they drink deep of the Cup of Affliction: the <hi>Hungarians,</hi> and the Eaſt part of <hi>Germany,</hi> begin to look blew upon it, for they fear a Famine, and <hi>Rome</hi> it ſelf begins to quake, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="year">
               <pb n="40" facs="tcp:50004:27"/>
               <head>Aſtrological Judgments for the Year <hi>1693.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <p>January the <hi>11,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> Eclipſed vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſible in ♌.</p>
                     <p>April the <hi>22,</hi> ☍ ♄ ♃ from ♊ and ♐.</p>
                     <p>July the <hi>6,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> Eclipſed inviſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble in ♋.</p>
                     <p>June <hi>23,</hi> ☉ Eclipſed viſible in ♋, and great.</p>
                     <p>July <hi>31,</hi> ☍ ♄ ♂ from ♊ and ♐.</p>
                     <p>December <hi>16,</hi> ☉ Eclipſed in ♑ inviſible.</p>
                  </note>ON the 22d day of <hi>April Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter</hi> make their Oppoſition from <hi>Gemini</hi> and <hi>Sagitarius,</hi> and there is alſo a remarkable Oppoſition between <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Mars</hi> from the ſame Signs, and we have no leſs than four Eclipſes between the Sun and Moon this year, from which Configurations we may rationally Judge of many ſtrange Actions and Calamities, which is likely to happen in ſeveral places of <hi>Europe;</hi> as thus, <hi>Spain</hi> is ſtill a loſer: Oh what a Diſtraction is there! and not only there, but in many more places beſides; for <hi>Bohemia, Sycily, Togata,</hi> and ſome part of the <hi>Turks</hi> Dominions, is threatned with Penury, that is, with ſcarcity of Grain, and other Proviſion: <hi>Rome</hi> is alſo much concerned herein, and if they have a Plague this year, let them think of me, for there is a bitter Potion prepared for that City; therefore <hi>Tom. Jeſuite</hi> prepare thy ſelf for a change; nay, the Pope himſelf alſo, <hi>Hungary, Dalmatia, Moravia, Miſnia, Sclavonia, Celtica, Chaldea, Phenicia, Orchinia, Damaſco, Siracuſa,</hi> and <hi>Rouenna</hi> do alſo lament, and well they may, for their Afflictions are great; <hi>Holland, Scotland, Granado, Burgundy, Ze<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land, Pruſia, Numidia,</hi> and indeed all Cities under <hi>Aries, Libra, Cancer,</hi> and <hi>Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pricorn,</hi> are much herein concerned; <hi>Holland</hi> is threatned with many Diſeaſes, and ſudden Deaths to the meaner ſort of People: <hi>Scotland, Granado,</hi> and <hi>Burgundy</hi> are alſo threatned with Mortality: The City <hi>Gemini</hi> muſt alſo expect to have a ſhare of this years Tranſactions, perhaps ſome of her Magiſtrates brought to Juſtice for their former Villanies, and in all probability ſome ſecret Plots may be diſcovered, and the chief Actors thereof brought to ſevere puniſhment: <hi>London</hi> is under the Government of <hi>Gemini,</hi> ſo is <hi>Flanders</hi> too; that Land is like to ſuffer extreamly by their own Folly, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="year">
               <head>Aſtrological Judgments for the Year <hi>1694.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <p>January the <hi>1,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> Eclipſed in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſible in ♋.</p>
                     <p>June the <hi>10,</hi> ☉ Eclipſed viſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble in ♋.</p>
                     <p>June the <hi>26,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> Eclipſed viſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble in ♑.</p>
                     <p>December the <hi>6,</hi> ☉ Eclipſed inviſible in ♐.</p>
                     <p>December the <hi>10,</hi> ☌ ♄ ♂ in ♑.</p>
                  </note>IN this year 1694 we have only four Eclipſes between thoſe glorious Lamps of Heaven, <hi>viz.</hi> Two of the Sun, and as many of the Moon; we have likewiſe a notable Conjunction of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Mars,</hi> which falls in Oppoſition to the viſible Eclipſe of the Sun, which happens <hi>June</hi> the 10th, in the firſt Face of <hi>Cancer;</hi> therefore all places under the Influence of <hi>Cancer, Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gitarius,</hi> and <hi>Capricorn,</hi> muſt expect many Troubles, Vexations and Calamities in this year 1694. Now <hi>Muſcovy</hi> have a care, or elſe ſome potent Enemy will invade thee, and bring greater Calamities upon thee, than thou haſt had hereto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore,
<pb n="41" facs="tcp:50004:27"/>
the <hi>Sweed</hi> and <hi>Tartars</hi> are alſo up in Arms, and if the <hi>Sweed</hi> be invaded tell him it is his own fault, becauſe I gave him timely warning before: the <hi>Danes</hi> aim, but to ſmall purpoſe: <hi>Scotland, Holland, Granado,</hi> and <hi>Burgundy</hi> muſt look to taſte of the bitter Cup: The <hi>Turk</hi> alſo grows very potent, and ſtill increaſes his Dominions, and <hi>Conſtantinople</hi> fears the Peſtilence: <hi>Zeland, Pruſia, Venice, Genoa, Lucas, Piſa, Bernyork, Macedonia, Thracia, Albania, Saxony, Spain, Dalmatia, Hungary,</hi> and <hi>Ireland</hi> muſt look to partake of this years Tranſactions: <hi>Oxford</hi> alſo muſt look to taſte of this year, for here is a violent ſtorm impending, and wo to that City when<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever it falls, for the Comet appeared in <hi>Capricorn,</hi> her Sign, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Alſo the Eclipſes of the Sun and Moon in the firſt and third Faces of <hi>Cancer</hi> denote many Diſeaſes to the Female Sex, and alſo ſudden miſerable and unexpected Deaths unto many: they alſo incline Mens minds to Arms, and to violate National Leagues deceit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully, under the pretences of Religion: They alſo cauſe a diſturbed Air, and ſtir up ſtrange kind of Weather, and variety of it, and that in thoſe Countries under the Sign <hi>Cancer;</hi> but thoſe Eclipſes of the Sun and Moon, in the ſecond Faces of <hi>Sagita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rius</hi> and <hi>Capricorn,</hi> portend the Death, or much Deſtruction unto ſuch Cattle as naturally bray, and of the bigger ſort of any ſuch Beaſts as are uſeful for Man, they alſo denote Incurſions of Armies into Neighbour Countries, Captivities, frequent uproars in the Souldiery, and that to all places under the Signs <hi>Sagitarius</hi> and <hi>Capricorn,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="year">
               <head>Aſtrological Judgments for the Year <hi>1695.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>I Shall judge the State and Condition of this year from the Configurations of the Planets,<note place="margin">
                     <p>May the <hi>18,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> Eclipſed in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſible in ♐.</p>
                     <p>June the <hi>1,</hi> ☉ Eclipſ. viſib. in ♊.</p>
                     <p>Aug. <hi>12,</hi> ☍ ♄ ♃ from ♍ and ♑.</p>
                     <p>Auguſt the <hi>23,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:trine">△</g> ♄ ♃ from ♍ and ♑.</p>
                     <p>November the <hi>10,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> Eclipſed viſible in ♉.</p>
                     <p>November the <hi>25,</hi> ☉ Eclipſed inviſible in ♐.</p>
                  </note> and Eclipſes of the Luminaries, which are as followeth; as thus, We have a notable Oppoſition between <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Mars,</hi> from <hi>Cancer</hi> and <hi>Capricorn,</hi> it falls the 12th of <hi>Auguſt,</hi> and on the 23d day of the ſame Month we have a <hi>Trine</hi> of ♄ and ♃ from ♍ and ♑; beſides, we have no leſs than four Eclipſes this year, two of the Sun, and as many of the Moon: The firſt Eclipſe of the Sun falls in <hi>Gemini, London</hi>'s Aſcendant, and the laſt E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clipſe of the Sun falls in <hi>Sagitarius;</hi> it is made in the ſecond Houſe, it threatens <hi>Spain</hi> with Deſtruction amongſt their Cattle, both great and ſmall; it alſo denotes many Robberies and inhumane Murthers in that Country, with ſtrange kind of Out-rages in <hi>Hungary, Dalmatia, Moravia, Sclavonia, Miſnia, Celtica,</hi> and in all places under <hi>Sagitarius;</hi> but the Eclipſe of the Sun in <hi>Gemini,</hi> which is made in the Eighth Houſe, bodes mortality to great Perſons, and that in <hi>Flanders, Brabant, Sar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dinia, Hircania, Armenia,</hi> and in <hi>London</hi> too; and becauſe <hi>Mars</hi> is Lord of the A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcendant, and poſited in <hi>Taurus,</hi> in Oppoſition to the ſame, therefore I judge we may expect to hear of popular Inſurrections in thoſe places under the Sign <hi>Gemini;
<pb n="42" facs="tcp:50004:28"/>
Mars</hi> in <hi>Taurus</hi> ſhews ſome troubles more than ordinary upon the Land of <hi>Ireland;</hi> and the viſible Eclipſe of the Moon in the laſt Face of <hi>Taurus,</hi> will leave ſome nota<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble Impreſſion upon that Land: Alſo, beſides, from theſe Configurations, we may Rationally Judge, the <hi>Swede</hi> is ſtill up in Arms againſt that Great and Potent Ene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>my the <hi>Tartar;</hi> and if I miſtake not, they both afflict <hi>Muſcovy</hi> and <hi>Poland,</hi> who will do a great deal of miſchief to his Neighbour Nations, if not timely prevented: <hi>Holland, Scotland, Burgundy, Granado, Zeland, Numidia, Africa, Calchis, Carthage, Conſtantinople, Venice, Tunis, York, Macedonia, Illiria, Thracia, Bofnia, Albania, Bulga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ria, Saxony, Haſſia, Oxford, India,</hi> are alſo threatned with many Vexations and Troubles in their Government, and that by reaſon of the Oppoſition of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Mars</hi> from <hi>Cancer</hi> and <hi>Capricorn;</hi> and to Conclude, I judge the <hi>Trine</hi> of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter</hi> in <hi>Virgo</hi> and <hi>Capricorn,</hi> will cauſe many Meetings and Treaties for a Recon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cilation of Peace to many places of <hi>Europe,</hi> but this is but a Lightning before Death; for the Conjunction of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Mars</hi> in <hi>Capricorn, December</hi> the 16th, Impedites their good Endeavours, and ſo deſtroys their Happineſs, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="year">
               <head>Aſtrological Judgments for the Year <hi>1696.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <p>February the <hi>21,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:trine">△</g> ♄ ♃ from ♍ and ♑.</p>
                     <p>May the <hi>6,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> Eclipſed viſible and total in ♏.</p>
                     <p>July the <hi>5,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:trine">△</g> ♄ ♃ from ♍ and ♑.</p>
                     <p>October the <hi>29,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> Eclipſed vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſible and total in ♉.</p>
                     <p>December the <hi>16,</hi> ☌ ♄ ♂ in <hi>27</hi> degrees of ♑.</p>
                  </note>WE have no leſs than two <hi>Trines</hi> this year be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter,</hi> from <hi>Virgo</hi> and <hi>Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pricorn, Saturn</hi> being in <hi>Capricorn,</hi> and <hi>Jupiter</hi> in <hi>Virgo;</hi> Oh, ſtrong will be the endeavours of the <hi>European</hi> Princes for an Univerſal Peace, throughout the whole Earth, and moſt People will have a ſtrong Confidence of the Concluſion thereof; but the weakneſs of <hi>Jupiter</hi> in <hi>Virgo,</hi> ſhews that it will not be accompliſht as yet, for ſuddenly after <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Mars</hi> meet in Conjuncti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on in <hi>Capricorn,</hi> and ſo deſtroys all former hopes and promiſes in a moment, and ſo hinders the good endeavours of <hi>Saturn,</hi> and inſtead of enjoying peace and quiet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, they fall together by the Ears; for <hi>Mars</hi> is all for Wars and Blood-ſhed, and not for Peace and Friendſhip, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> In the next place we ſhall conſider thoſe two great and famous Eclipſes of the Moon in <hi>Taurus</hi> and <hi>Scorpio;</hi> as thus, The Eclipſe of the Moon in <hi>Scorpio,</hi> declares many Seditions, Murthers, and all manner of wretched<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs ſucceds, Mankind oppreſſed with abundance of obnoxious Diſeaſes, and theſe generally in <hi>Norway, Bavaria, Metagony, Comogena, Cappadocia, Idumea, Maurita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nia, Feſs, Gethulia, Catalonia,</hi> &amp;c. But the Eclipſe of the Moon in <hi>Taurus</hi> threatens the Death of ſome Queen this year, in ſome Country under the Influence of <hi>Taurus; Ireland</hi> is alſo very violent to thoſe poor <hi>Engliſh</hi> which inhabit that Country: Oh the Treacherouſneſs of thoſe Villains, will they never forbear to do miſchief; but let them know that hard is their Fate, for they are threatned with thin Crops of Corn, which will be deſtroyed either by Famine, or a Rebellious ſort of People: <hi>Holland</hi> is alſo threatned with much Dammage, by the Seas over-flowing its accuſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med Bounds, they are alſo threatned with loſs of many Ships abroad, and that by violent Storms and Tempeſts: The <hi>Muſcovites</hi> are ſtill diſturbed, and know not when they ſhall reſt in peace: The <hi>Turk</hi> keeps his Sword drawn, and the <hi>Tartarians</hi>
                  <pb n="43" facs="tcp:50004:28"/>
are not returned home as yet, neither is <hi>Swedeland</hi> ſatisfied, nor <hi>Poland</hi> contented, but <hi>England</hi> reſts upon a Rock, and her Foundation ſtands unſhaken, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
               <q>
                  <l>That which is fixt upon a Rock, I am ſure will laſt</l>
                  <l>
                     <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ntil the late Evening of the World be paſt, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </q>
            </div>
            <div type="year">
               <head>Aſtrological Judgments for the Year <hi>1697.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>IN this year we have no leſs than three Eclipſes of the Sun and Moon,<note place="margin">
                     <p>May the <hi>10,</hi> ☉ Eclipſed invi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſible in ♉.</p>
                     <p>May <hi>25,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> Eclipſed inviſible in ♏.</p>
                     <p>Auguſt <hi>27,</hi> ☍ ♄ ♂ from ♌ and ♒.</p>
                     <p>September <hi>14,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:quadrine">□</g> ♄ ♃ from ♏ and ♒.</p>
                     <p>October <hi>19,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> Eclipſed viſible in ♉.</p>
                  </note> likewiſe a famous Oppoſition be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween thoſe two Malefacts, <hi>viz. Saturn</hi> and <hi>Mars</hi> in <hi>Leo</hi> and <hi>Aquarius:</hi> We have alſo a ſquare of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter,</hi> from <hi>Scorpio</hi> and <hi>Aquarius,</hi> from which Configurations, I judge <hi>Holland, Scotland, Ireland, Burgundy, Granado,</hi> and <hi>Ruſſia</hi> will indure a longer time of Sorrow and Affliction, yet they are not alone, for hard is the Fate of that potent place <hi>Italy,</hi> for the ſquare of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter</hi> doth cauſe her to feel the dire effects of their triple Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>junction in <hi>Leo,</hi> to purpoſe; for the <hi>Turk</hi> ſtill gains ground upon her, and thereby inlarges his own Dominions: The <hi>Tartars</hi> are alſo afflicted by the <hi>Polanders,</hi> and <hi>Muſcovia, Sycily, Apalia, Bohemia, Emilia, Sabinia, Phenicia, Bulgaria, Saxony, Gaunt, Oxford, Moſel, Piemont, Sarmatia,</hi> all theſe places have a potent Enemy to deal withall, neither are their ſufferings alone, for ſeveral more places under <hi>Tau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rus</hi> are like to ſuffer Pennury, that is, want of Proviſion; for the Luminaries E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clipſed in the firſt Face of <hi>Taurus,</hi> is ſufficiently hurtful to the Corn upon the Earth, and great Cattle, for they are hereby threatned with many prodigious Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eaſes, which will generally rage amongſt them; theſe Eclipſes do alſo afflict ſuch as are Negotiators, Sollicitors, Agents, or are generally employed in Mens Affairs, or in the Publick; they alſo compel Men to undertake unneceſſary buſineſſes, and bring to nought all Factions undertaken by the former ſort of People, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="year">
               <head>Aſtrological Judgments for the Year <hi>1698.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>IN this year we have only two Eclipſes,<note place="margin">
                     <p>March <hi>31,</hi> ☉ Eclipſed inviſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble in ♈.</p>
                     <p>May the <hi>24,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:quadrine">□</g> ♄ ♃ in <hi>20</hi> degr. of ♏ and ♒.</p>
                     <p>September <hi>23,</hi> ☉ Eclipſed in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſible in ♎.</p>
                     <p>December <hi>22,</hi> ☌ ♄ ♂ in ♒.</p>
                  </note> and thoſe both of the Sun, and not viſible, but we have a remarkable Conjunction of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Mars</hi> in <hi>Aqua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rius,</hi> and alſo two ſquare Aſpects between <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter,</hi> from <hi>Scorpio</hi> and <hi>Aquarius, Saturn</hi> being in Oppoſition, and <hi>Jupiter</hi> in <hi>Quartile</hi> to the very De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gree of their great Conjunction, 1682, from which Configurations I may rationally judge, that this is like to be a year of much action, and eſpecially to <hi>Italy,</hi> for that is threatned with no leſs than Confuſion, and a to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tal ſubverſion of the Triple Crown alſo, although it may not be fully compleated this year, yet thoſe which live to ſee this time, will ſee a great ſay ſet to it; for
<pb n="44" facs="tcp:50004:29"/>
when ſome wiſe Princes are in Conſultation how to conclude of Peace, War like a Thunderbolt ſuddenly breaks out, and the Pope hereby thinking to benefit himſelf, or his Church, by Incroachment, indangers his Papacy, and almoſt, if not quite, Confounds his Primacy, and Conſumes his Patrimony; this year ſeems to be the time of his down-lying, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> The Sea will alſo ſwell with great Navies of Ships, and thereby cauſing many great Sea-fights, and in all probability <hi>England</hi> may have a hand in it too, if it has it will come off victorious, to their great Honour and Glory, and then the <hi>Roman</hi> Clergy ſhall run up and down from place to place, and find no ſhelter, yea the whole Conclave of Cardinals ſhall tremble and ſhake for fear, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The power of <hi>France</hi> is alſo brought very low, even as low as <hi>Pharaohs lean kine,</hi> for the late Wars hath deſtroyed many thouſands of the poor Inhabitants, and that by the means of the <hi>Roman</hi> Clergy, and the pride of an inſulting Governour: <hi>Ire<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land</hi> and <hi>Holland</hi> hath alſo drank deep of the Cup of Affliction; and <hi>Englands</hi> Foun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dation ſtands firm and unſhaken, God continue it, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The Eclipſe of the Sun in the laſt Face of <hi>Aries,</hi> deſtroys the leſſer Cattle, as Hogs, Sheep, Goats, Conies, Hares, and is the fore-runner of Lamentation, Woes, and Mourning unto mortal men, or moſt ſorts of Men, and the death of ſome No<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble Woman; but the Eclipſe of the Sun in the Second Face of <hi>Libra,</hi> portends the Death of ſome Eminent Prince, or King, or Noble Man, and for breach of Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtoms ſtirs up Sedition, and deſigns a Famine: Thoſe places under <hi>Aries</hi> and <hi>Libra,</hi> are moſt likely to ſuffer and feel the Effects of theſe Eclipſes, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="year">
               <head>Aſtrological Judgments for the Year <hi>1699.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <p>January the <hi>14,</hi> ⚹ ♄ ♃ in ♐.</p>
                     <p>March <hi>5,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> Eclipſed viſible in ♍.</p>
                     <p>March <hi>21,</hi> ☉ Eclipſed viſible in ♈.</p>
                     <p>Auguſt <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>0,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> Eclipſed viſible in ♓.</p>
                     <p>September <hi>13,</hi> ☉ Eclipſed vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſible and great, ♎.</p>
                     <p>September <hi>13,</hi> ☍ ♄ ♂ from ♌ and ♒.</p>
                     <p>October the <hi>10,</hi> ⚹ ♄ ♃ from ♐ and ♒.</p>
                  </note>THis year we have four Eclipſes of the Luminaries, <hi>viz,</hi> two of the Sun, and as many of the Moon: The ſecond Eclipſe of the Sun will be viſible and bigger than any Eclipſe that hath been ſeen in <hi>England</hi> this fifty years, it falls in the beginning of <hi>Libra,</hi> on the 13th day of <hi>September,</hi> about eleven of the Clock before Noon, at which time there will be an Oppoſition be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Mars</hi> from <hi>Leo</hi> and <hi>Aquarius,</hi> that will aggravate the Effects thereof to purpoſe; there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore I judge great will be the actions of this year, and that for a ſettlement of Peace throughout the whole World, for we have no leſs than two <hi>Sextiles</hi> of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupiter,</hi> from <hi>Sagitarius</hi> and <hi>Aquarius,</hi> each Planet poſſeſſing his own Houſe, the one beginning the year, and the other ending the year, but before there is a perfect Concluſion made, all Nations will be troubled with Rumours of Wars, every Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gion preparing Armies, Traffick prohibited both by Sea and Land: The main Sea ſhall hugely ſwell with mighty Tempeſts, ſo that the Sea in many places ſhall over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>flow its accuſtomed Bounds, cauſing violent Inundations in many Countries; alſo terrible Sea Fights this year, ſuch as hath not been before, occaſioning the Water to look more Red than the Red Sea, ſo great a Drought, and ſo great a want of
<pb n="45" facs="tcp:50004:29"/>
Water will appear in many places, that multitudes of People will dye in many places for meer want of Water; great Plagues and Mortality alſo cover many places of the Earth, and ſo deſtroy Man-kind; there will alſo appear ſuch noyſome ſwarms of Fowls and Flies that will devour the Corn upon the Ground, cauſing great Famine and Dearth of Corn in many Nations of <hi>Europe,</hi> and ſuddenly after unexpectedly appears a great Conquerour, the World being filled with the Fame of this Man, who ſuddenly, like <hi>Auguſtus,</hi> gives Peace unto the whole Earth, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="year">
               <head>Aſtrological Judgments for the Year <hi>1700.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>IN this year we have only two Eclipſes of the Moon,<note place="margin">
                     <p>February the <hi>28,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> Eclipſed viſible in ♍.</p>
                     <p>Auguſt the <hi>18,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> Eclipſed in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſible in ♓.</p>
                     <p>December the <hi>29,</hi> ☌ ♄ ♂ in ♓.</p>
                  </note> the one in <hi>Virgo,</hi> and the other in <hi>Piſces,</hi> likewiſe a Conjunction of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Mars</hi> on the 29th of <hi>De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cember,</hi> in <hi>Piſces,</hi> the great Dignities of <hi>Jupiter,</hi> from which Configurations, I judge there will be no great matter of buſineſs in Agitation this year, only every Nation will be endeavouring to ſettle it ſelf, for all Princes have a ſtrong inclination for Peace, and the continuance thereof; for moſt Princes will make Leagues more firm and ſtrict than formerly; here will be almoſt a new World, for our Farmers now take pleaſure in their Husbandry; the Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chants hath proſperous Returns, and the Mechanicks quick Trading, every Man repairs his former loſſes; and ſoon after follows the deſtruction of <hi>Rome,</hi> with the downfall of the Pope: <hi>England</hi> be thou content, and return God the due praiſe for the many Bleſſings he affords thee annually; for the late <hi>Sextil</hi> of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>piter</hi> in their own proper Houſes, doth promiſe Peace and Tranquility to thee, and indeed all the World: Now old men live their full years, and our Youth grow up to Mens Eſtates, <hi>&amp;c,</hi> Yet I muſt tell you by the way, that theſe Eclipſes of the Moon in <hi>Virgo</hi> and <hi>Piſces,</hi> with the Conjunction of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Mars</hi> alſo, will leave ſome notable impreſſion upon thoſe places under the Signs wherein they happen, and what thoſe Effects will be, I ſhall leave you to examine Mr. <hi>Lilly</hi>'s <hi>Annus Tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>broſus,</hi> Printed 1652.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="year">
               <head>Aſtrological Judgments for the Year <hi>1701.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>IN this year we have no leſs than four Eclipſes of the Luminaries,<note place="margin">
                     <p>January the <hi>28,</hi> ☉ Eclipſed in viſible in ♒.</p>
                     <p>February the <hi>11,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> Eclipſed viſible in ♍.</p>
                     <p>July the <hi>2,</hi> ☉ Eclipſed viſible in ♌ and great.</p>
                     <p>Auguſt the <hi>7,</hi> 
                        <g ref="char:Moon">☽</g> Eclipſed invi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſible in ♒.</p>
                     <p>October the <hi>2,</hi> ☍ ♄ ♂ from ♍ and ♓.</p>
                  </note> 
                  <hi>viz.</hi> two of the Sun and as many of the Moon; we have alſo an Oppoſition between <hi>Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turn</hi> and <hi>Mars</hi> from <hi>Virgo</hi> and <hi>Piſces:</hi> The firſt E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clipſe of the Sun is in the ſecond Face of <hi>Aquarius:</hi> The ſecond Eclipſe of the Sun falls in the ſecond Face of <hi>Leo;</hi> but the firſt Eclipſe of the Moon falls in the firſt Face of <hi>Virgo;</hi> and the ſecond Eclipſe of the Moon, happens in the laſt Face of <hi>Aquarius,</hi> but what
<pb n="46" facs="tcp:50004:30"/>
they portend, or are the fore-runners of, that I ſhall leave to Aſtrologers to deter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mine when the time cometh: For I am apt to believe that ſome Nations will not ſee an end of their Troubles till Dooms-day, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Therefore let no Man think himſelf happy, until the day of his Death, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> According to the <hi>Rudolphin</hi> Ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles in Mr. <hi>Coley</hi>'s <hi>Clavis</hi> of Aſtrology: The next Conjunction of <hi>Saturn</hi> and <hi>Jupi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter</hi> will fall in <hi>May</hi> 1702, in that Equinoctial Sign <hi>Aries,</hi> the Aſcendant of <hi>England.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Readers, in this my Aſtrological Judgment for 20 years, I have conſidered every year the Figure of the Suns Revolution, as well as the Configurations of the Supe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riour Planets and Eclipſes, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
               <q>Nemo ſine crimine vivit.</q>
               <q>
                  <l>That Man never breathed yet, nor never ſhall,</l>
                  <l>That did all well, and had no fault at all.</l>
               </q>
            </div>
            <div type="treatise">
               <head>Here followeth a Treatiſe of the Peſtibence, both for Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vention and Cure thereof, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>IN the firſt place, let ſuch as would avoid this Diſeaſe, avoid the fear thereof, for fear changeth the Blood into the Nature of the thing feared, the Imagination ruling the Spirits Natural, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Secondly, Let the Body be kept ſoluble, if it be not ſo Naturally, take a Scruple of <hi>Pillalae Ruffi Peſtilentialis,</hi> at Night when you go to Bed, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Thirdly, And if the Body be full of Blood, bleed ſo much as ſtrength and age will permit, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Fourthly, Take a Spoonful of Vinegar of Squills, three or four times a day, <hi>viz.</hi> at ten of the Clock in the Morning, and juſt after Dinner, and at four in the Afternoon, and likewiſe after Supper. Fifthly, Take the quantity of a Ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zel-Nut of Methridate, it is thus made; gather half a handful of green Rue, any Sunday morning a little after Sun-riſing, then take ſix blew Figs, and ſix Walnuts, and forty Juniper Berries, and a little Bay-Salt, beat theſe altogether into an E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lectuary. Sixthly, Let all Paſſions and Perturbations of mind be avoided, and like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe all violent motions; and likewiſe, I ſhall adviſe all thoſe which love their Healths to avoid the drinking of Wine and ſtrong Drink, for all ſuch things as theſe inflame the Blood. Seventhly, Let all People keep their Houſes pure and clean, for a foul Houſe is like ſoft Wax, ſitting to receive any impreſſion; alſo let there be a good Fire kept therein; and let your Diet be of good Juice, quick of digeſtion, and be ſure you eat thoſe things which are ſharp with your Meats, as Vinegar, Verjuice, Oranges, Juice of Lemmons, and Citrons, or Pomgranets, let all Fruits be avoided, except ſuch as are ſower; let not the Stomach be over-charged with exceſs of Meat or Drink, and in Summer time let the Blood be cooled with cool Herbs, as Endive, Lettuce, Purſlain, Succory; and let your Drink be Whey clarified with them; let your ſmells be of <hi>L<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>udanum Storax, Calamitis, Camphire,</hi> Cinnamon, Nutmegs, Wood of Aloes, Liquid Storax, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Laſtly, Theſe things being taken inwardly are preventional and reſiſt the Diſeaſes, <hi>viz. Angelica</hi> Roots, <hi>Zodoary, Bolearmeniack, Terra limina,</hi> Methridate, Treacle, <hi>Tormentil,</hi> and <hi>Petaſitis</hi> Roots, and Citron Pills; thus much for Prevention.</p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="47" facs="tcp:50004:30"/>In the next place I come to Proviſion for it when prevention is too late; and firſt of all, that Proviſion may be timely, I begin with the Signs of one Infected, which are 12: The firſt is when the outward Members be cold, and the inward Members burning hot: the ſecond is heavineſs, wearineſs, ſloth, and indiſpoſition of the whole Body, and difficulty in breathing: the third is pain and heavineſs in the Head: the fourth is carefulneſs of mind, and ſadneſs: the fifth is a marvellous inclination to ſleep for the moſt part, for ſometimes watching and raving vex them: the ſixth is the flowing of the Eyes: the ſeventh is the loſs of appetite: the eighth is immoderate thirſt, and often vomiting: the ninth is bitterneſs, and dryneſs of the Mouth: the tenth is the pulſe is ſwift, ſmall, and deep: the eleventh is the Urine for the moſt part thick and ſtinking: the twelfth and moſt certain ſign of all is, if there appear ri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſings behind the Ears, under the Arm-holes, or in the Groins, without any manifeſt cauſe known, or, and if Carbuncles ariſe ſuddenly in any other Member, theſe when they riſe ſhews Naturh is ſtrong and able, becauſe it thruſteth the venom from it; in the beginning of the Sickneſs, nay, many times before the Body feels it ſelf ſick; now theſe riſings appearing in any place, ſhew which of the Vitals is moſt afflicted with the Diſeaſe; for if they appear about the Ears, the Brain is moſt annoyed, by reaſon that is the purging place of the Brain; if the riſing appear under the Arms, then the Heart is the part afflicted, for that is the purging place of the Heart; but and if it appear in the Groin, the Liver is moſt infected, for the Groin is the purging place thereof; but if no riſing appear at all, it fore-ſhews Nature to be weak, and not able to expel and thruſt forth the Venome; but when thoſe ſpots appear that are called Tokens, they ſhall ſhew that the whole Body Univerſally is Corrupted, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> If you feel your ſelf infected firſt upon a full Stomach, take a Vomit preſently; alſo in the beginning of the Diſeaſe, let the Diſeaſed Perſon Blood on that ſide that the riſing appears, as if it ſhould happen in the Neck, bleed in the <hi>Cephalica</hi> on that Arm, <hi>viz.</hi> if it be on the right ſide, bleed the right Arm, if on the left ſide, bleed the left Arm, if the riſing appear under the Arm, bleed in the <hi>Baſilica</hi> of the Arm on that ſide the riſing appears, but if it appear in the Groin, breathe a Vein in the Ancles of the ſide it appears on, but if none at all appear, conſider which parts are moſt grieved with Pains and Aches, and proceed in Blood-letting, according to the former Rules; Sweating alſo is a very Sovereign remedy, which you may effect by ſome ſuch Medicines as theſe, <hi>viz.</hi> Methridate, Venice-Treacle, <hi>Mathiolus</hi> his great Antidote, Black-Cherry-Water, Serpentary Roots, <hi>Electuarium de Ovo,</hi> the Blood being cooled with this or the like Juleps, and let him or her drink no other Drink: take Harts-horn and Ivory, of each one Ounce and a half; of the flowers of Violets, Bur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rage, Bugloſs, Clove-gilly-flowers, Roſemary, and Marigolds, of each two Drams; of the Roots of <hi>Petaſitis,</hi> and <hi>Zedoary,</hi> of each three Drams; of the Roots of <hi>Scor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zonera,</hi> one Ounce, boyl them all in a Pottle of Water until it comes to a Quart, and when it is almoſt boyled, add to it Saffron and <hi>Chochaneal,</hi> of each ten Grains, then ſtrain it, and add to it Syrrup of Violets, Clove-gilly-flowers, and <hi>Meleſſaphylli fernelii,</hi> of each one Ounce, Oyl of Sulphur, 12 Drops, let this be drank ſo often as the ſick is a dry; if the Diſeaſed be aſtringent, keep the Body ſoluble with Clyſters, and let them be refreſhed and ſtrengthened with Cordials; and if they ſleep not, provoke ſleep with <hi>Diaſcordium,</hi> but have a care of <hi>Opiates</hi> in the beginning of the Diſeaſe; if they vomit much, as ſome do vomit up all they do eat and drink, ſtay it with Spirit of Mint, or bake a Toaſt very well, then dip it in Wine Vinegar, chew
<pb n="48" facs="tcp:50004:31"/>
a little of this while it is hot, and hold the reſt to your Noſe, and it will cloſe up the mouth of the Stomach; and if any ſwelling do riſe, conſider firſt whether it be likely to brake or not, that you may know by its lying deep in the Fleſh and looking white, it is not likely to break, you muſt then anoint it with Oyl of Lillies, or Oyl of Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>momell; but if it riſe to a Head, and look Red, and lye not deep in the Fleſh, it will break, then take a young Pidgeon, pull off the Feathers from the tail, and hold her bare Fundament to the ſwelling, and it will draw out all the Venome; ſome lay Venice Treacle to it, for Venice Treacle draweth the Venome to it, but ſometimes the ſwelling falls down again, and is black, this ſhews great danger of Life, and that comes through cold taken; therefore you muſt be very careful, and ſee that you do not take cold in this Diſeaſe, for it is very dangerous; but when it is too late to pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vent; the Remedy thereof, preſently take a Pidgeon, and with a ſharp Knife, ſlit her through the breaſt to the Back, break her open and apply her yet alive to the place, if this do no good, apply a cupping Glaſs to the place, for a deſperate Diſeaſe muſt have a deſperate Cure; for what is it that a Man will not do to ſave his Life, ſo long as there is hopes, when the ſore is broken, apply a <hi>Milliot</hi> Plaiſter to it, and tent it with <hi>Linimentum Arcei,</hi> and make no great haſte to heal it up: Laſtly, And if Tokens appear, which by moſt people is affirmed and firmly belived, to be an infal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lible ſign of Death, let the Perſon ſo infected be let Blood, and when you have ſo done, give ſuch Phyſick as ſhall be thought fit by an able Phyſitian, for the cleanſing of the Body from all ill humours, and let the ſick have ſuch Cordials as ſhall cool the Blood and ſtrengthen Nature; then ſee, through the providence of God, whether Nature will not be able to rout the Diſeaſe. Another Remedy for thoſe that have the Tokens, which is ſomewhat more deſperate than the former, as thus, whilſt natu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral heat remains, wrap up the ſick Perſon in a Blanket wet in cold Water, and that will cauſe a violent Sweat, and thereby purges out the Corruption from the Blood, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> For a Plague Sore Boyl, or Carbuncle, Bay-ſalt dryed, and beaten into fine Powder, and well incorporated with the yolks of Eggs, makes an excellent Plaiſter, being ſpread up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on Leather: This alſo is an excellent remedy for the Plague, take Ivy Berries when they are Ripe, and dry them, then take half a Dram of the Powder of them in Plantain-Wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, and ſweat upon it: another, if a piece of Angle-Gold be put into Juice of Lemmons, and after 24 hours taken out again, and a little <hi>Angelica</hi> Root in powder put into it, and drunk by ſuch as have the Plague, cures to admiration, but you muſt gather the <hi>Angelica</hi> on a Sunday juſt as the Sun riſes, becauſe it is a Herb of the Sun; and the Gold ſhould be put in at the ſame time, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> So much for the Prevention and Cure of the Peſtilence, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
               <q>
                  <l>But if Nature frown, the Caſe is hard,</l>
                  <l>And if Art want, the matter all is marr'd.</l>
               </q>
               <p>Do not we know that the Learned Phyſician giving a Medicine to his ſick Patient, expecteth not that it ſhould immediately operate, ſome hours he alloweth for the Medicines operation: God is our Phyſician, the Heavens his ſtore-houſe, or Shop, the Sun, Moon, and Stars his Inſtrumental Medicines and Drugs, their motion, his time he gives in operation: If Phyſick work not, as the Learned Doctor conceiveth it ought to do, <hi>(aliquid latet)</hi> there is an obſtruction he little thought of: Therefore if I miſtake or fail in theſe my Prognoſticks, perhaps the Great <hi>Jehovah</hi> hath reſerved the Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour for ſome more worthy and deſerving perſon than I am, therefore blinds my Senſes, or elſe permits me not to ſee, or fore-tell what thoſe Heavenly Meſſengers are the fore-runners of, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
